<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: mac | andres marrugo]]></title>
  <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/categories/mac/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-30T01:24:57-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andres Marrugo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Always Late to The Party]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/22/always-late-to-the-party/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-22T00:11:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/22/always-late-to-the-party</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="to-tweet-or-not-to-tweet">To Tweet or Not to Tweet</h2>

<p>It always seems I’m late to the party. For several years I pondered on the idea of joining <a href="https://twitter.com/" title="Twitter">Twitter</a>, but it never really made much sense to me – at least at the time – to join a social network where there were hardly any friends of mine<sup id="fnref:fn1"><a href="#fn:fn1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>. Big mistake, that actually <em>is</em> one of the cool things about twitter. Unlike Facebook, it <em>does</em> provides an open space suitable for engaging in discussions, albeit short, of all sorts with interesting people who don’t really have to be your “friend.”</p>

<p>It turns out that shortly after joining twitter most people<sup id="fnref:fn2"><a href="#fn:fn2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> were already considering abandoning it in favor of <a href="https://join.app.net/" title="Join the Movement - App.net">App.net</a>. For the time being <a href="https://join.app.net/" title="Join the Movement - App.net">App.net</a> seems like a <em>niche</em> thing, and most people seem to continue on twitter. Whether that stays that way for the next year or so depends on twitter and their recent policy changes that could well endanger the platform as we know it today. </p>

<!--more-->

<h2 id="its-all-about-the-editor">It’s All About The Editor</h2>

<p>For quite a while it seemed that everywhere I looked, geeks where rejoicing and feeling proud of their text editor of choice: <a href="http://macromates.com/" title="TextMate — The Missing Editor for Mac OS X">Textmate</a>. I did look into it a couple of times, but I always thought it ways a bit too expensive for me. </p>

<p>For the most part it seemed I had always managed to get by with the tools at my disposal, I really didn’t feel like I needed something else.
I would use the builtin Matlab editor for writing Matlab code. As regards LaTeX – for writing papers – I would use the open source and free (as in beer) <a href="http://www.xm1math.net/texmaker/" title="Texmaker (free cross-platform latex editor)">Texmaker</a>. I really wasn’t aware of the exciting and cool features of <em>advanced</em> text editors like Textmate or <a href="http://www.vim.org/" title="welcome home : vim online">Vim</a>. </p>

<p>For as long as I can remember, I’ve been a computer enthusiast, but a lone one. I never did have close friends that were into the sort of things I liked. I was never really ostracized, but I <em>was</em> the “nerd” nevertheless. </p>

<p>This brief digression is not without a purpose, which is to bring forth the fact that despite being a geek, I’ve never been part of a geek community of any sort. And this influenced my way of life and how I – before social networks – ended up finding out about the latest and coolest thing. More often than not, late and when it wasn’t really a <em>new</em> thing. The text editor dilemma is proof to my lack of geeky-social interaction.</p>

<p>Before I bought Textmate, I <em>did</em> do a little background check to see what was happening to its development. Apparently it was being not-so-actively developed, but version 2.0 was on the way. I had managed to somehow convince myself that it was totally worth it and that I would write my thesis with it. </p>

<p>Shortly after I bought it, it went open source, and to the impression of some: abandoned. It seems that for quite some time, everyone had been moving to Sublime text or BBEdit. Late to the party once again. I just can’t stop thinking that if somehow I had looked into it a bit more, if I had participated more on forums and different communities all of this would have ended differently. I <em>can</em> however say, that I am still using Textmate 1,  and I’m enjoying my self quite a bit.</p>

<h2 id="a-static-or-dynamic-blog">A Static or Dynamic Blog</h2>

<p>Technically speaking I’ve been bloggin since 2010. However, I must be honest and admit that for about the first year of my <a href="http://copiancestral.wordpress.com/" title="Between the Candle and the Star | Academia, Computing, and other topics.">(former) blog</a> I hardly posted a thing or two. It was a <a href="http://wordpress.com/" title="WordPress.com — Get a Free Blog Here">wordpress.com</a> blog and for nearly the last year or so, I began posting more regularly and I was really enjoying myself. I rapidly got accustomed to wordpress; so much, that I felt trapped in the platform, and I needed more customization to set things my way. Well, for the looks of it, I had to leave wordpress.com and move my blog somewhere else in order to do just that.</p>

<p>I kept blogging there, while I looked around to explore my options. It was interesting that this time I was <em>also</em> late, but not so much in the sense that I was able to catch a lot of people during their <a href="http://www.macdrifter.com/migrating-to-pelican-extracting-wordpress-data.html" title="Migrating to Pelican - Extracting WordPress Data">migration from a dynamic blog to a static one</a>. I’m not going to go through the details of why I chose a static blog, but it does have its advantages with respect to a dynamic one, like wordpress. </p>

<h2 id="getting-stuff-done">Getting Stuff Done</h2>

<p>As a final section for this already long post, I’d like to mention how I’ve also been late to the whole GTD movement (if there is such a thing). It’s amusing how shortly after I started to actually read David Allen’s book on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Getting_Things_Done" title="Getting Things Done - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia">“Getting Things Done”</a>, some people were already arguing </p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“whether GTD [was] valid after more than 10 years without any real “update”.”</p>

  <p>– <strong>Sven Fechner</strong>, <a href="http://simplicitybliss.com/the-state-of-getting-things-done" title="The State of Getting Things Done — SimplicityBliss">The State of Getting Things Done.</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>I can’t really say for my self, if it is still valid. I can, however, say that it still seems to make sense in the philosophy behind it, probably not so much in the methodology. But hey, what can I say, I haven’t even finished the <em>goddamn</em> book.</p>

<p>I’ve been late, as always, to many fascinating events of recent years – at least the geeky ones it seems. But I’ve come to accept that as a reality of mine. These days I can say that I try to keep myself more in the loop by following several interesting people on the web, whether it be via their blogs, twitter, or podcasts. This  seems a bit of a remedy to my bad timing, but hey everyone’s entitled to do things their way. I’m still struggling to actually find what <em>is</em> “my way”, but I’m in no hurry. There probably isn’t any <em>real</em> answer, <a href="http://www.macdrifter.com/2012/08/fiddle-sticks.html" title="Fiddle Sticks">I reckon the search is more valuable than the goal itself.</a></p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:fn1">
      <p>I <em>still</em> have few close friends on twitter; most of them are rarely active. As regards Facebook, I cannot say the same. <a href="#fnref:fn1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:fn2">
      <p>When I say <em>most</em> people, I actually mean the majority of people worth following. <a href="#fnref:fn2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Convert Image to PDF with Automator and Imagemagick]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/18/image-to-pdf-with-automator-and-imagemagick/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-18T22:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/18/image-to-pdf-with-automator-and-imagemagick</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I often use <a href="http://www.imagemagick.org/script/index.php">Imagemagick</a> for image manipulation<sup id="fnref:fn2"><a href="#fn:fn2" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>. However, for simple conversion of an image to another format or similar things I have to go to the terminal and type something like the following</p>

<pre><code>convert somefile.png somefile.pdf
</code></pre>

<p>Which is quite simple, and much better than opening preview -&gt; export<sup id="fnref:fn1"><a href="#fn:fn1" rel="footnote">2</a></sup>-&gt;select pdf-&gt; and hit save. But typing that for more than one image is <em>also</em> tedious. So, I decided I’d better create a service that would essentially do the following.</p>

<p>It would take the selected finder items, mainly images in <code>png</code>, <code>jpeg</code>, or whatever, and convert all of them to <code>pdf</code>. Simple. <!--more-->  The automator service is shown in the following image. It does exactly what I’ve described.</p>

<div class="aic" style="width:500px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/8099954950/" title="to-pdf-automator-script by copiancestral, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8045/8099954950_8d97fab95f.jpg" width="500" height="252" alt="to-pdf-automator-script" /></a><br />
Automator service.</div>

<p>The shell script is quite simple. Because the <code>convert</code> command from Imagemagick is not a command in bash, I have to call it with the whole path. The rest of that one-liner is a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sed"><code>sed</code></a> call to substitute  whatever extension the input file has (with the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regular_expression" title="Regular expression - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia">regex</a> <code>\..*</code>) to <code>.pdf</code>, and that’s it. Here’s the script.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><figcaption><span>convert-to-pdf   </span></figcaption>
 <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="k">for </span>f in “<span class="nv">$@</span>”
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">do</span>
</span><span class='line'>  /opt/local/bin/convert “<span class="nv">$f</span>” &lt;code&gt;echo <span class="s2">&quot;$f&quot;</span>|sed <span class="s2">&quot;s/\..*/.pdf/&quot;</span>&lt;/code&gt;
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">done</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>
<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:fn2">
      <p>As a matter of fact, now that I’ve finally upgraded to Mountain Lion, Imagemagick stopped working. Had to reinstall with macports.<a href="#fnref:fn2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:fn1">
      <p>“Save as” in the old days, prior to OS X 10.7.<a href="#fnref:fn1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My blog post writing workflow with Dropbox and Hazel]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/15/blog-post-writing-workflow-dropbox-hazel/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-15T23:44:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/15/blog-post-writing-workflow-dropbox-hazel</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It may seem that, for the most part, I’ve been blogging about blogging. No matter how pointless it seems, I <em>do</em> think that this could prove useful to someone, in the same way I have benefited from others while setting up this site<sup id="fnref:foo2"><a href="#fn:foo2" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>.</p>

<p>One of the things I like about having an <a href="http://octopress.org/" title="Octopress">Octopress</a> driven <code>txt</code>-only blog is that I have the liberty to set things my way. The topic I am addressing here is that of writing blog posts on different devices<sup id="fnref:foo1"><a href="#fn:foo1" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> with the help of Dropbox<sup id="fnref:foo5"><a href="#fn:foo5" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> and <a href="http://www.noodlesoft.com/hazel.php" title="Noodlesoft | Hazel">Hazel</a>. I’m still working out the whole remote blogging thing, this is but the first stage of a soon-to-be remote blogging workflow with Octopress. </p>

<!--more-->

<!-- When I say "different devices" I actually mean three:

- A Macbook Pro at the office, almost always on.
- A Mac Mini at home, often on, but not necessary logged in my user.
- An iPod Touch, always with me. -->

<h2 id="my-blog-post-writing-workflow">My blog post writing workflow</h2>

<p>Ideally any blog post starts with an idea that I write down in a text file named <code>runx-blog_ideas-qqq.txt</code><sup id="fnref:foo3"><a href="#fn:foo3" rel="footnote">4</a></sup>. This is done either on any of the two Macs using <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/project/nvalt/" title="nvALT 2.1 - Notational Velocity Fork">nvAlt</a> or on my iOS device using any text editor<sup id="fnref:foo4"><a href="#fn:foo4" rel="footnote">5</a></sup>. I <em>always</em> write in <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/" title="Daring Fireball: Markdown">Markdown</a> (technically I <em>mostly</em> write in <a href="http://fletcherpenney.net/multimarkdown/" title="MultiMarkdown">Multimarkdown</a>, but that’s another thing). </p>

<p>After I decide that this idea is ready to become a draft, I create a text file that follows the same name convention for Octopress (<code>2012-10-14-Post-title.text</code>) on a folder named <code>_drafts</code> that resides in the <code>source</code>. You might have noticed that the extension is not <code>.markdown</code> and that is because I was having issues <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/fixing-spotlight-indexing-of-markdown-content/" title="Fixing Spotlight indexing of Markdown content - Brett Terpstra">making Hazel read the contents of markdown files</a>. So I opted for <code>.text</code> which is technically the same as <code>.txt</code>, but I would differentiate them as drafts and most <em>importantly</em> <a href="http://macsparky.com/2009/6/3/sorting-and-moving-documents-with-hazel.html" title="Sorting and Moving Documents with Hazel — MacSparky">Hazel will be able to do its magic</a>.</p>

<p>The underscore (<code>_</code>) on the name of the drafts folder is so that it won’t be deployed, just as the posts folder</p>

<pre><code>source/
|__ _drafts/
|__ _posts/
</code></pre>

<p>With the help of <a href="http://www.ergonis.com/products/typinator/" title="Typinator - the fastest text expander in town">Typinator</a> on my mac or <a href="http://smilesoftware.com/TextExpander/touch/index.html" title="TextExpander touch: iOS Typing Shortcuts for iPhone and iPad">Textexpander</a> on my iPod I create the yaml header like this</p>

<pre><code>--- 
layout: post 
title: "Post title" 
date: 2012-10-14 23:28 
author: Andres Marrugo 
comments: true 
published: false 
categories: [blog] 
--- 
</code></pre>

<p>Notice that <code>published: false</code>, which means <em>it is a draft</em>. When I’m finished with the post I’ll change it to <code>true</code>. </p>

<h3 id="the-syncing">The Syncing</h3>

<p>The Syncing is done via Dropbox, because any iOS text editor comes with Dropbox support. iCloud has still a long way to go. Because my octopress folder does not reside in the Dropbox folder I made symlinks on my Mac to the <code>_posts</code>, <code>_drafts</code>, and <code>images</code> folders so they get synced </p>

<pre><code>ln -s ~/octopress/source/_posts/ ~/Dropbox/PlainText/blog/_posts
ln -s ~/octopress/source/images/ ~/Dropbox/PlainText/blog/images
ln -s ~/octopress/source/_drafts/ ~/Dropbox/PlainText/blog/_drafts
</code></pre>

<p>On any other machine they become actual folders.</p>

<h3 id="automating-with-hazel">Automating with Hazel</h3>

<p>Ideally I would like to change the <code>published: false</code> to <code>true</code> and have it posted to my site, but it still requires some workarounds and this is why for the time being my hazel magic script only moves the file to the <code>_posts</code> folder when the published option changes to <code>true</code>. I then generate the site and deploy it manually, but this will soon be automated as well.</p>

<p>There are actually two Hazel rules for this. It first monitors the <code>_drafts</code> folder for files whose content contains the phrase <code>published: true</code>. When this happens the file gets moved to the folder <code>_posts</code>.</p>

<div class="aic" style="width:500px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/7913589162/" title="drafts-move-to-posts-hazel by copiancestral, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8038/7913589162_551eed930a.jpg" width="500" height="243" alt="drafts-move-to-posts-hazel" /></a><br />
Move file to _posts folder.</div>

<p>Then the second rule is for the <code>_posts</code> folder. If the extension is <code>text</code> (which means it was a draft that recently got moved) it will run a shell script.</p>

<div class="aic" style="width:500px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/7913591478/" title="posts-modify-latest-post-hazel by copiancestral, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8458/7913591478_f75d933161.jpg" width="500" height="356" alt="posts-modify-latest-post-hazel" /></a><br />
Modify latest post.</div>

<p>The shell script is the following. What it does is to replace the date with the current date – you see, several days could’ve passed since I created the draft – in both the yaml header and the file name. And the other thing it does is to change the extension to <code>.markdown</code>.  </p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><figcaption><span>Move to posts folder   </span></figcaption>
 <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>&lt;/p&gt;
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;h1 <span class="nv">id</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&quot;replace-yaml-header-date-to-current-date&quot;</span>&gt;Replace yaml header date to current date&lt;/h1&gt;
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p&gt;sed “s/<span class="o">[</span>0-9<span class="o">]{</span>4<span class="o">}</span>.*:<span class="o">[</span>0-9<span class="o">]{</span>2<span class="o">}</span>/&lt;code&gt;date <span class="s1">&#39;+%Y-%m-%d %H:%M&#39;</span>&lt;/code&gt;/” <span class="nv">$1</span> &amp;gt; tmp &amp;amp;&amp;amp; mv tmp <span class="nv">$1</span>&lt;/p&gt;
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p&gt;mydate<span class="o">=</span><span class="k">$(</span>date ‘+%Y-%m-%d’<span class="k">)</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">fname</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="k">$(</span><span class="nb">echo</span> <span class="nv">$1</span> | sed “s/text/markdown/”<span class="k">)</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c"># Rename file to current date</span>
</span><span class='line'>mv <span class="nv">$1</span> &lt;code&gt;echo <span class="nv">$fname</span> | sed <span class="s2">&quot;s/[0-9]\{4\}.*-[0-9]\{2\}-[0-9]\{2\}/$mydate/&quot;</span>&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p&gt;
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>It may look like there’s not much automation, but if you think that this runs on my Mac while I’m writing it in my iPod Touch, then it gets really interesting, and the possibilities are almost infinite. Besides, updating the post date, moving files and changing extensions are quite tedious tasks by themselves. To make it automatically generate and deploy the site I’d have to add several more lines to the script, but I’m ok with how it is for now. </p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:foo2">
      <p>Special thanks to <a href="http://www.neilsmithline.com/">Neil Smithline</a> for helping me out on <a href="https://github.com/imathis/octopress/issues/708">the two blogs one domain issue</a>.<a href="#fnref:foo2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:foo1">
      <p>My Mac or my iPod touch.<a href="#fnref:foo1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:foo5">
      <p>I can’t really write this post without mentioning two posts that served as inspiration and reference: <a href="http://instant-thinking.de/2012/08/03/synced-and-scheduled-blogging-with-octopress/">“Synced and scheduled blogging with octopress”</a> and <a href="http://www.macstories.net/stories/my-dropbox-writing-workflow/" title="My Dropbox Writing Workflow">“My Dropbox Writing Workflow.”</a><a href="#fnref:foo5" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:foo3">
      <p>In some future post I’ll explain my note taking workflow and how I name files. In this case I use <a href="http://www.kungfugrippe.com/post/453204090/q-trick">Merlin Mann’s <code>q</code> trick</a> and the <code>runx</code> stands for running notes.<a href="#fnref:foo3" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:foo4">
      <p>I use several editors, but mainly <a href="http://bywordapp.com/" title="Byword &bull; A Simple Text Editor for Mac and iOS">Byword</a>, <a href="http://writeup.prasannag.com/" title="WriteUp - with Dropbox">WriteUp </a>, <a href="http://www.secondgearsoftware.com/elements/" title="Elements &mdash; Dropbox powered text editor for iPhone, iPad and iPod touch from Second Gear">Elements</a>, and <a href="http://nebulousapps.net/" title="Nebulous Notes">Nebulous Notes</a>.<a href="#fnref:foo4" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spanish keyboard and Aperture]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/07/spanish-keyboard-and-aperture/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-07T00:36:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/07/spanish-keyboard-and-aperture</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="aic" style="width:320px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/8060866808/" title="Mac keyboard by copiancestral, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8030/8060866808_dc3b5dc915_n.jpg" width="320" height="240" alt="20121007-PA077266" /></a><br />
My new keyboard.</div>
<p>It’s been quite a while since I’ve grown accustomed to switching back and forth between an english keyboard at home and a spanish keyboard at work. Like anything, at first it takes a while to get fully accustomed, but all in all it isn’t too bad. This week my English keyboard at home died, so I bought a new one this time in Spanish, because that was what they had at the store. </p>

<p>One of the things I don’t like of the spanish keyboard <sup id="fnref:fn1"><a href="#fn:fn1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> is that most (if not all) applications design the shortcuts assuming an English keyboard. Therefore, what could be single key shortcut in the English keyboard becomes a double key shortcut in the  Spanish keyboard. And that’s not all. </p>

<!--more-->

<p>It just so happens that in some applications, in my case Apple Aperture there are some really nice single key shortcuts like left square bracket (<code>[</code>) for rotating an image counterclockwise, but in the spanish keyboard the bracket, while being in the same place has to be typed with the option (<code>⌥</code>) key. </p>

<p>For some unknown reason Aperture doesn’t recognize this double key shortcut as the single key shortcut I’m trying to reproduce. As a matter of fact it assumes I’m pressing (<code>⌥ `</code>), where the back-tick is the other character sharing the same key as the left square bracket.<sup id="fnref:fn2"><a href="#fn:fn2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup></p>

<div class="aic" style="width:150px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/8060947094/" title="Square bracket by copiancestral, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8034/8060947094_174fee44ff_q.jpg" width="150" height="150" alt="Square bracket" /></a><br />
Square bracket on spanish keyboard.</div>

<p>I have googled a bit about this topic and in an <a href="https://discussions.apple.com/thread/1452719?start=0&amp;tstart=0">apple discussion</a> this was somewhat discussed, but to no great length. And the only solution for the time being is to go to <code>'Aperture' &gt; 'Commands' &gt; 'Customize...'</code>. But I’m still not comfortable changing the default commands in Aperture. I really liked the single key shortcuts for rotating an image and stuff like that. Let’s see how this ends up.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:fn1">
      <p>Or any other keyboard that’s not the English one.<a href="#fnref:fn1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:fn2">
      <p>The reason I hadn’t noticed this is that I don’t use Aperture at work.<a href="#fnref:fn2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[a service for writing day one footnotes inline]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/01/a-service-for-writing-day-one-footnotes-inline/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-01T22:31:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/01/a-service-for-writing-day-one-footnotes-inline</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently wrote about <a href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/09/29/footnotes-in-dayone/">inserting footnotes in Day One</a> and how it could be achieved with the new markdown support. I realize that ideally Day One should support multimarkdown footnotes, but this has not arrived yet. It could well be planned for a future release, but I’ll stick to my solution for the mean time.</p>

<p>One of the tedious things about my solution to footnotes in <a href="http://dayoneapp.com/">Day One</a> is that you have to <em>do</em> everything manually. The insertion of the footnotes <em>plus</em> the formatting, not to mention keeping count of the number of footnotes. For one or two footnotes this doesn’t seem like a big issue. But for several more it gets complicated.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> You have to put the superscript (<code>^</code>), the number of the footnote, the horizontal line (which I think necessary) and the footnote itself. Therefore, I thought I could automate this–somewhat.</p>

<!--more-->

<h2 id="here-comes-the-magic-script">Here comes the magic script</h2>

<p>So I though I’d ask <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/">Brett Terpstra</a><sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> for advice, to see if this could be automated somehow. At the moment he’s probably quite busy with the premiere of his book <a href="http://60tips.com/">60 Mountain Lion Tips</a>, which promises “to turn you into a Mac ninja”. </p>

<p>Despite that, I remembered he had released a service for <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/a-service-for-writing-multimarkdown-footnotes-inline/">writing multimarkdown footnotes inline</a>.  The idea is that you write your text like this</p>

<pre><code>This is the regular text(*This is the footnote*), and you can drop the footnote in at any point.
</code></pre>

<p>You run the service and you get something like this</p>

<pre><code>This is the regular text[^fn1], and you can drop the footnote in at any point.

[^fn1]: This is the footnote
</code></pre>

<p>According to Brett “one nice thing about this syntax is that–if you’re previewing as you write–it italicizes the output to differentiate it until you’ve used the service to move it out of the main text.” So it’s a win-win situation. </p>

<p>I decided I would modify the script, even though I am a <em>neophyte</em> in ruby. The modification is practically nothing, so all the credit goes to Brett. Here’s the modified script</p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/3814178.js"> </script>

<p><strong>Update</strong> on Oct 2, 2012 – Brett took a look at the code and gave it the thumbs up.</p>

<p>I will definitely not go into the details of the script, but I’ve tried it and it works. The only thing I didn’t bother to make work was the part of the code that made sure that footnote reference titles aren’t duplicated if you have existing formatted footnotes in the document. It’s commented out, but feel free to further modify it or make any suggestions. </p>

<p>For the same input as above you should get this</p>

<pre><code>This is the regular text^1, and you can drop the footnote in at any point.

****
1. This is the footnote
</code></pre>

<p>Here’s a <a href="http://d.pr/f/t4ff">download link</a> so you can download it as a system service. You’ll have to move it to <code>~/Library/Services/</code>. Enjoy!</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>I don’t usually write long entries in Day One, but hey there’s always a day when I feel <em>so</em> inspired, I could write a short story if I wanted to.<a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>Brett is a computer geek that makes awesome things (most for free) like <a href="http://markedapp.com/">Marked</a> or <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/project/nvalt/">nvAlt</a>. He blogs at <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/">brettterpstra.com</a>, and for what it seems is one of the nicest guys on the internet.<a href="#fnref:2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
