<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: life | andres marrugo]]></title>
  <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-25T02:04:19-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andres Marrugo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On (re)learning things]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2015/01/29/on-relearning-things/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-29T22:47:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2015/01/29/on-relearning-things</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>My favorite topic in an introductory differential equations course is mechanical and electrical vibrations. I enjoyed learning about it as a student and I enjoyed teaching it later. (Or more accurately, I enjoyed being exposed to it as a student and really learning it later when I had to teach it.)</p>

  <p>John D. Cook on <a href="http://www.johndcook.com/blog/2013/02/19/mechanical-vibrations/">Mechanical vibrations</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>I’ve always thought that education is about learning, as much as parenting is about maturing and growing up. On the parenting side, you can’t really teach your kids how to live – <a href="http://www.radiolab.org/story/288746-future-cant-control/" title="A Future You Can't Control - Radiolab">you can’t even imagine the kind of world they will have to live from the time they’re born</a> – but you <em>can</em> expose them to the best things you know. In doing so, they can at least have the chance to form an opinion on the many matters of life, they’ll surely make mistakes, but I bet they won’t regret much. </p>

<p>Education is a difficult topic. Everyone has something to say about it, yet no one seems to have true answers. I do think that education is much more about being exposed to something, rather than being taught that something. There’s an incredible difference between the two things.  </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not Collapsing the Wave Function]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2014/01/31/not-collapsing-the-wave-function/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-31T09:32:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2014/01/31/not-collapsing-the-wave-function</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today in <a href="http://www.thisamericanlife.org/radio-archives/episode/399/contents-unknown" title="Contents Unknown | This American Life">“This American Life”</a> I was listening to an episode about hidden truths. It was really interesting to find out about a secret letter that the prime minister of Britain writes to every commander of a nuclear submarine. It supposedly contains instructions on what to do if the nation has been wiped out and if the commander should retaliate or not. It poses a mystery on what the contents are, even more so because every time there’s a new prime minister in office the letters are destroyed unread.</p>

<p>There are many questions that come about in knowing what the contents of the letter are. But to my understanding it is a way of reassuring your people that both possibilities exist. To retaliate or not. It is like delaying the final call on a difficult decision. Something akin to a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schrodinger_cat" title="Schrödinger's cat - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia">Schrödinger cat situation</a>.  </p>

<p>I’ve thought of this for while and I’ve come to understand that many people actually <em>like</em> to live their lives this way. Not wanting to know certain things, or more precisely clinging to the hope that a certain aspect in one’s life does not turn out to be what we fear so much. Keeping both options open (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wave_function" title="Wave function - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia"><em>not collapsing the wave function</em></a>) is probably a reassuring situation, relieving anxiety and allowing one to continue living unmoved by the cold hard reality. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ The Perils of Talking Too Much]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2013/06/10/the-perils-of-talking-too-much/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-10T22:07:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2013/06/10/the-perils-of-talking-too-much</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="aic" style="width:500px"><img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/5279729/blog-pics/medium_5731336614.jpg" alt="" /><br />
photo credit: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/mkorsakov/5731336614/">mkorsakov</a> via <a href="http://photopin.com">photopin</a> <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/">cc</a></div>

<p>All too often I see people who simply talk too much.<sup id="fnref:fn1"><a href="#fn:fn1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> Wether what they speak is nonsense or <em>even</em> meaningful things, there’s a limit to how much one can tolerate. </p>

<p>By talking too much –  and too often – we miss out on many things. We don’t let others speak (which to my understanding is common courtesy), and worse of all we lose our capacity to empathize with others. We can’t <em>read faces</em> well while uttering words out of our mouths continuously. Loosing that feedback is what prompts us to speak without pause and with no care for what the people around us may feel. It’s what turns you into a prick. We’re just <em>too</em> focused on ourselves to care about others. </p>

<!-- more -->

<p>Having no feedback at all is dangerous, it really is. You tend to get the feeling that you’re always right. Usually, people are too polite to interrupt you and <a href="http://contentmarketingsuite.com/actionbar/15826/Are-You-A-Power-Poisoned-Boss" title="Are You A Power-Poisoned Boss?">bring you down a notch</a> and say, <em>it takes two to converse! This is no lecture</em>. A conversation is about sharing <a href="http://www.martynemko.com/articles/do-you-talk-too-much_id1371" title="Do You Talk Too Much?">and paying attention to your conversation partner’s needs.</a></p>

<p>It is no surprise that by talking too much we may alienate our loved ones and friends from our lives. They’ll avoid us and our utterances at all times. It is this kind of behavior that we have to be  careful about.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:fn1">
      <p>I used to be one of those, I know better now. <a href="#fnref:fn1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Secularism]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2013/04/10/new-secularism/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-10T11:48:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2013/04/10/new-secularism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="aic" style="width:500px"><img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/5279729/blog-pics/medium_2911020311.jpg" alt="" /><br />
photo credit: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pablomoroe/2911020311/">Pablo Moroe</a> via <a href="http://photopin.com">photopin</a> <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/">cc</a>.</div>

<p>Before Darwin it certainly was <a href="http://choiceindying.com/2011/03/02/could-you-be-an-intellectually-fulfilled-atheist-before-darwin/" title="Could you be an intellectually fulfilled atheist before Darwin? | Choice in Dying">very difficult to be an atheist</a> or a nonbeliever – that is, an intellectually fulfilled one.<sup id="fnref:fn1"><a href="#fn:fn1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> At least that’s how <a href="http://www.talkorigins.org/indexcc/CA/CA602_1.html" title="CA602.1: An intellectually fulfilled atheist">Richard Dawkins</a> usually puts it and I quite agree with him. It was not that the scientific method<sup id="fnref:fn2"><a href="#fn:fn2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> didn’t exist at the time, it was that the mystery of life was too big a mystery to even consider tackling through the ways of science. Yet that was what Darwin did. </p>

<p>The topic of this post does not have to do with Darwin, at least in a direct sense. The other day I was listening to <a href="http://www.pointofinquiry.org/" title="Point of Inquiry">Point of Inquiry</a>, a podcast from the center of inquiry.<sup id="fnref:fn5"><a href="#fn:fn5" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> They had <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frans_de_Waal" title="Frans de Waal - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia">Frans de Waal</a> on and he talked about his latest book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Bonobo-Atheist-Humanism-ebook/dp/B007Q6XKEY"><em>The Bonobo and the Atheist</em></a>. There was a moment during the interview that the host, Chris Mooney, referred to him as being an atheist to which he replied saying </p>

<!-- more -->

<blockquote>
  <p>I am not necessarily an [atheist], because atheism has now come to stand for being very strongly opposed to religion which is really not what I am, I prefer to call my self either a <em>nonbeliever</em> or an <em>apathetic</em> meaning that, the agnostic doesn’t know if god exists, the atheist denies the existence of god, and <em>I basically don’t care</em>. I don’t think it is an important or interesting problem to discuss god. And as a scientist, I don’t know what to do with the god question. It will never be resolved, certainly not by science. </p>

  <p><strong>– Frans de Waal</strong>, On <a href="http://www.pointofinquiry.org/frans_de_waal_the_bonobo_and_the_atheist/">Point of Inquiry: Frans de Waal - The Bonobo and the Atheist</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>I can truly relate to his words. As much as I identify with people like Richard Dawkins or Sam Harris, being an atheist does not have to mean being opposed to religion. I can do that without being one. As a matter of fact religion and the institutions that promote it have done so much wrong to mankind that the logic behind them falls apart rather quickly. </p>

<p>What I can’t seem to get around my head is that despite that, religion is still a creation of humans and if I want to take the scientist’s approach I should accept it for what it is. That doesn’t mean, like de Wall suggests, that it cannot be replaced with something else. In his book, he argues that morality is something that is older than our species. Research suggests that many primates, and other animals, have a sense of morality. Meaning that they have impulses and self control mechanisms to resolve conflicts, to determine rules, etc. </p>

<p>In fact <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massimo_Pigliucci" title="Massimo Pigliucci - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia">Massimo Pigliucci’s</a> book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Answers-Aristotle-Science-Philosophy-Meaningful/dp/0465021387"><em>Answers for Aristotle</em></a> attempts to solve that problem by saying that we should lead a life that is both philosophically and scientifically pertinent. Going back to the whole being opposed to religion issue, I say, denying god gets us nowhere. The existentialist questions still remain and it says nothing about what’s the best way to lead a life. Our society is too big and complex to pretend that we shouldn’t pursue such questions. However, we should use the best tools we’ve got for the job, and in the twenty-first century these are not religion or theology. </p>

<p>To conclude I would like to say that we shouldn’t really attack religion for what it is or for being wrong, we should instead try to show the way with the best tools we have. Resolving conflict without invoking god. Discussing real life issues with the best evidence we can find. Addressing our questions knowing wholeheartedly our limits. </p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:fn1">
      <p>Yes, before Darwin we had <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Hume">David Hume</a>, but his reasoning was solely based on the fact that <a href="http://choiceindying.com/2011/03/02/could-you-be-an-intellectually-fulfilled-atheist-before-darwin/" title="Could you be an intellectually fulfilled atheist before Darwin? | Choice in Dying">God isn’t a good explanation</a> for biological design. It was Darwin who came up with one.<a href="#fnref:fn1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:fn2">
      <p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_scientific_method#Galileo_Galilei" title="History of scientific method - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia">Galileo Galilei</a> is often referred to as the father of the scientific method. <a href="#fnref:fn2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:fn5">
      <p>“A think tank promoting science, reason, and secular values in public policy and at the grass roots”.<a href="#fnref:fn5" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Book for my Son]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2013/03/27/a-book-for-my-son/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-27T21:21:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2013/03/27/a-book-for-my-son</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the latest <a href="http://www.70decibels.com/generational/2013/3/24/027-aaron-hillegass-and-teaching-experts.html" title="70Decibels - Generational - 027 - Aaron Hillegass and Teaching Experts">Generational podcast</a> episode <a href="http://www.bignerdranch.com/instructors/hillegass.shtml">Aaron Hillegass</a> told <a href="http://www.macdrifter.com/" title="Macdrifter">Gabe</a> that he wrote his <a href="http://www.bignerdranch.com/book/objective-c_programming_the_big_nerd_ranch_guide">Objective-C</a> book with his ten-year-old in mind. </p>

<p>I found this to be quite interesting and truly inspiring. By writing the book “for his son,” he made sure anyone could actually read and understand it, but also he was deeply motivated to get it right. I wouldn’t want my son to read a crappy book. </p>

<p>If I ever had to write a guide about how to be (stay) motivated on a project this would definitely be there.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
