<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: writing | andres marrugo]]></title>
  <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/categories/writing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2020-03-02T23:37:49-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andres Marrugo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Writing my thoughts down]]></title>
    <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2013/01/02/writing-my-thoughts-down/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-02T22:52:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2013/01/02/writing-my-thoughts-down</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="aic" style="width:500px"><img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/5279729/blog-pics/medium_3989921751.jpg" alt="iPod touch" /><br />
photo credit: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/chiarashine/3989921751/">chiarashine</a> via <a href="http://photopin.com">photopin</a> <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/">cc</a></div>

<p>As is often the case, ideas come about in the most unexpected moments. Lately, I’ve found myself taking notes while walking to work, while waiting for a coffee in front of a bending machine, or like now while getting dressed for work. </p>

<p>It’s become a habit of mine to write what I think, when I think it. My iPod touch has enabled that. I could well have pen and paper with me at all times, but I’m not used to that and nothing beats the digital format. </p>

<!--more-->

<p>I journal much more now than ever before, and that’s thanks to apps like <a href="http://dayoneapp.com/" title="Day One | A simple Journal for iPhone, iPad and Mac App Store">Day One</a> or <a href="http://agiletortoise.com/drafts" title="Drafts - Agile Tortoise">Drafts</a>. Writing  my thoughts down has never been easier. And, to tell you the truth, it’s <em>liberating</em>. It’s like <a href="http://5by5.tv/b2w/96" title="5by5 | Back to Work #96: Compensatory Muscles">Merlin Mann</a> says, “your brain has permission to think at all times.” And, as Melissa Donovan says in her book <a href="http://amzn.com/0615547850">101 Creative Writing Exercises</a>, “Journaling…promotes observation, self-awareness, and reflection, all skills that great writers must possess”, (by way of <a href="http://writeitsideways.com/learning-to-see-the-good-in-bad-writing/" title="Learning to See the Good in Bad Writing">Christi Craig</a>). My journaling has come a long way since I started using <a href="http://dayoneapp.com/" title="Day One | A simple Journal for iPhone, iPad and Mac App Store">Day One</a> last year. Some blog posts start there, or even certain personal emails too. Journaling helps me to reflect upon my thoughts and to make important decisions. </p>

<p>I’ve always been fond of writing, yet I’ve never had such an intimate relationship with my thoughts and my inner self. I believe that writing brings about the best in me. Through writing I can look at my human face and recognize my afflictions and ghosts. </p>

<p>Even as I sit here on my bed, tying my shoelaces, I feel an urge to get my thoughts out. I had never experienced this strong desire before. I, however, am totally aware that the more I write, the more I feel this urge. It’s quite fascinating and at times I just can’t help myself. </p>

<p>Happy new year to all my readers. Hope you had a nice time during the holidays and that you soon start your 2013 projects motivated and committed to getting things done – at least that’s my main purpose for this year.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Careless email writing]]></title>
    <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2012/12/26/careless-email-writing/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-26T10:16:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2012/12/26/careless-email-writing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="aic" style="width:500px"><img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/5279729/blog-pics/medium_2756494307.jpg" alt="Text editing." /><br />
photo credit: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/nicmcphee/2756494307/">Unhindered by Talent</a> via <a href="http://photopin.com">photopin</a> <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/">cc</a></div>

<p>I read the other day an email that desperately needed some editing. Writing without editing is pretty much the same as speaking with little attention to what we are saying. The great advantage of the <em>written form</em> over the spoken one is that you <em>can</em> go back an edit. Not editing what you write is both a poor use of the written form and a sign that you don’t care much for the person that will read your message. </p>

<!--more-->

<p>It’s not that a typo is not allowed, no one is perfect. But to write something without punctuation is just insane. All too often I hear people say that, because they are not writers or journalists they are somehow excused of writing poorly. I think it is just plain laziness. It’s a laziness that reads as our lack of interest for a craft so important to us by which we express what we feel and think.</p>

<p>How is it, that common sense doesn’t rouse in these situations? Why is it so difficult to realize that a 500+ word email written in a single paragraph without punctuation is just <em>illegible</em>. It costs so much to get the ideas out of that mess. The laziness to which I refer does service to no one, and buries even the meaning of your well-intended message.</p>

<p>So do yourself a favor and go back and edit the message a bit before hitting the send button.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ My reflection in a mirror of prose]]></title>
    <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2012/11/16/my-reflection-in-a-mirror-of-prose/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-16T07:02:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2012/11/16/my-reflection-in-a-mirror-of-prose</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I like to write, for writing reminds me of who I am, who I want to be, and where I come from. It is no mistery that I enjoy it, but that doesn’t make it any easier. </p>

<p>I often get compliments on my writing, but still, I think there’s a long way to go before I feel more comfortable with it – I still struggle over single words or sentences. </p>

<p>Lately, I’ve been rediscovering myself in many different ways. I find myself more aware of everything – and that is probably not the most interesting thing – if not by chance, by fate, but I do feel different. I certainly am not the same person I was a while ago. I write more, which means <em>I exit my body more often</em>. </p>

<!--more-->

<p>I write about my writing, for it serves as confession and a means to <em>see</em> my reflection in a mirror of prose. A reflection of what I think, and of who I am. It is no coincidence that by writing I often find answers to my problems or get a glance of the next step I should take. </p>

<p>Writing is <em>almost</em> certainly  not for everyone, at least in the sense of writing for the fun of it. I hardly know people – in person that is<sup id="fnref:fn1"><a href="#fn:fn1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> – that write out of pure pleasure, let alone people that <em>truly</em> make a living out of writing. </p>

<p>Writing is an art, but is also a skill. A skill that – despite natural talent – requires time and effort in developing. Like <a href="http://www.mcsweeneys.net/authors/colin-nissan">Colin Nissan</a> says in the <a href="http://www.mcsweeneys.net/articles/the-ultimate-guide-to-writing-better-than-you-normally-do">“Ultimate guide to writing better than you normally do”</a></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Writing is a muscle. Smaller than a hamstring and slightly bigger than a bicep, and it needs to be exercised to get stronger. Think of your words as reps, your paragraphs as sets, your pages as daily workouts. Think of your laptop as a machine like the one at the gym where you open and close your inner thighs in front of everyone, exposing both your insecurities and your genitals. Because that is what writing is all about.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Yes, it’s about exposing yourself and becoming stronger in the process. </p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:fn1">
      <p>In the <em>virtual</em> world, I <em>do</em> know a number of people that write for the fun of it and are lucky enough to make a living from it. <a href="#fnref:fn1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm writing the site I want to read]]></title>
    <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/the-site-i-want-to-read/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-19T23:32:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/the-site-i-want-to-read</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="aic" style="width:240px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/8004479709/" title="a day in the life of striatic ~ end of day accident by striatic, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8313/8004479709_2bfe1eb43a_n.jpg" width="240" height="320" alt="a day in the life of striatic ~ end of day accident" /></a><br />
photo by striatic.</div>

<p>If there’s something I learned from the famous talk “<a href="http://www.43folders.com/2009/03/25/blogs-turbocharged">149 Surprising Ways to Turbocharge Your Blog With Credibility!</a>” by <a href="http://daringfireball.net/">John Gruber</a> and <a href="http://www.merlinmann.com/">Merlin Mann</a>,  was that one should make a great effort to write as if the people you admire we’re going to read your work. This is true even if the people you admire are fictional, or like in Gruber’s case, an idealized version of himself. 
I like to think that this piece of advice is as valid for writing/blogging as it is for anything else you do in life.
<!--more--> </p>

<p>I can certainly say that I personally don’t know most of the people I admire,<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> which is fine by me. But I don’t write exclusively for them. Quite often, if not always, I write for myself.<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> I write as a way to remind my future self of what it felt to be me in the past.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> I write to the better version of myself, in the hopes that by doing so, my worse version recognizes his mistakes and learns from them. </p>

<p>In some ways my ideal reader <em>is</em> the better version of myself. More often than not I find myself reading my own articles several times after they’ve been published. It certainly is not a narcissistic thing,<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">4</a></sup> I just really like to feel proud of what I make. This is why <em>I write the site I want to read</em>. </p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>This, without much doubt will continue to stay this way, for some of them are dead, and believing in the afterlife is plain foolishness. <a href="#fnref:2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:4">
      <p>I had been meaning to write this post for quite a while, but hadn’t found time to do so. However, Gabe Weatherhead’s post on his <a href="http://macdrifter.com/2012/09/audience-and-my-multiple-personalities.html">Audience and Multiple Personalities</a> prompted me to write it in a flash. Thanks Gabe. <a href="#fnref:4" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Trust me, one easily forgets how things felt in the very moment you were experiencing them. And all that is left is a vague reminder of what happened. <a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3">
      <p>Or so I like to think. <a href="#fnref:3" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's all about writing]]></title>
    <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/its-all-about-writing/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T22:56:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/its-all-about-writing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="air" style="width:240px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/7986686420/" title="Typewriter by copiancestral, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8041/7986686420_96859c1d73_m.jpg" width="240" height="240" alt="Typewriter" /></a><br />
photo by fiddle oak.</div>

<p>In the past year or so I’ve read a lot about how different people get their stuff done, specially when referring to writing. There are some people who just <a href="http://cristianmihai.net/2012/07/16/writing-habits/"><em>wait</em> for inspiration</a> to knock on their doors, whereas others simply <em>force</em> themselves to write every day. Inspiration is a tricky thing, but no one can’t deny that when it comes, it certainly <em>feels</em> good. In the words of <a href="http://cristianmihai.net/">Cristian Mihai</a></p>

<!--more-->

<blockquote>
  <p>“Back when I was very young, I used to write in the moments of extreme inspiration, when my fingers were fueled by a frantic feeling of freedom and everything I wrote seemed to achieve a sort of elusive grandeur”.  <br />
– <strong>Cristian Mihai</strong>, <a href="http://cristianmihai.net/2012/07/16/writing-habits/"><em>Writing Habits</em></a>.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The forcing yourself to write goes more in the lines of what Merlin Mann describes as “<a href="http://www.43folders.com/2006/05/17/procrastination-draft">turning your procrastination into shitty first drafts</a>”<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>. The way I see it is that writing is <em>hard</em>, and no one has all the answers. But as evident as it sounds, no writing is produced if you never sit down to write. This is clearly something everyone will agree on. </p>

<p>A couple of months ago I read  a nice piece on <a href="http://blog.macademic.org/2011/05/07/academic-writing-beyond-the-software/">academic writing</a> by Aleh Cherp.  In this article he gave several tips from different authors about the art of writing. One of the books he recommended was “<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Writing-Social-Scientists-Chicago-Publishing/dp/0226041085">Writing for Social Scientists: How to Start and Finish Your Thesis, Book, or Article</a>”, and one of the ideas he puts forth is that thinking and writing are not two separate activities. It is naïve to assume that you should come up with ideas and then express them on paper. He goes on to state that </p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Writing is thinking and a lot of our systematic thinking can only occur when we are writing. Thus, waiting for the ideas to come is one of the biggest mistakes young writers make. Instead, the only way to create your ideas is to actually start writing.   <br />
– <strong>Aleh Cherp</strong>, <a href="http://blog.macademic.org/2011/05/07/academic-writing-beyond-the-software/"><em>Academic writing: inclining your mind</em></a>.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I really couldn’t say what kind of writer I am<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup>, but I will say that only through writing I’ve become a better writer. Writing is one of those rare skills that if you practice it a lot you <em>can</em><sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> become better at it, but you’ve got to have at least a little bit of talent in order to progress significantly. Besides, if all you do is write, you’ll probably not end up writing something interesting.  You have to oscillate between “the writing” and “the inspiration” in order to produce something meaningful. This reminds me of a phrase by Merlin Mann, “The art of art is about oscillating between your time and attention.” A nice way to express this graphically is with the following plot which I shamelessly reproduced from a post by Cameron Plommer on <a href="http://cameronplommer.com/balancing-inspiration-with-doing-work/">the problem with inspiration</a></p>

<div class="aic" style="width:500px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/7986664555/" title="Time and attention. by copiancestral, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8297/7986664555_6eef57a2da.jpg" width="500" height="200" alt="Time and attention." /></a></div>

<p>The graphic is self explanatory in that you have to oscillate between getting information and making something. If all you do is read, read, and read, you’ll most likely never end up <em>making</em> anything. You never give yourself the opportunity to <em>make</em> something, let alone something awesome. On the other hand if <em>all you do</em> is write, write, and write, you’ll probably never produce an interesting <em>thing</em> because you never stopped for a while to realize <em>who you are</em> and  <em>what the heck you’re doing</em>.  </p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>The concept of shitty first drafts comes from <a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12543.Bird_by_Bird">Anne Lamott’s Bird by Bird book</a>.<a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>If I could call myself a writer.<a href="#fnref:2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3">
      <p>There’s no guarantee. <a href="#fnref:3" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
