<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: life | andres marrugo]]></title>
  <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-02-23T23:38:52-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andres Marrugo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life immutable]]></title>
    <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2015/10/10/life-inmutable/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-10T22:34:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2015/10/10/life-inmutable</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a data-flickr-embed="true" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/22093344571/in/datetaken/" title="Life immutable."><img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/724/22093344571_5a128fb7da.jpg" width="500" height="379" alt="Life immutable." /></a><script async="" src="http://agmarrugo.github.com//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>

<p>We often live worrying about the future and longing for a less troublesome past; like when we were kids. I know that not everyone had a <em>perfect</em> childhood. I certainly did not, but I still had my moments in which my joy was true and worry free. Those moments are precious to me. </p>

<p>Adulthood has many upsides when viewed from a teenager’s perspective; the opposite is also true. If only they could talk to each other. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Praise of Slow]]></title>
    <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2015/08/07/in-praise-of-slow/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-07T23:53:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2015/08/07/in-praise-of-slow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have a recurrent discussion with my wife. </p>

<p>She likes to do most things as <em>fast</em> as possible. </p>

<p>I like to pause and think about things, and do them often <em>slowly</em>. At my pace. </p>

<p>I think that if you do things too quickly you might not be fully aware of what you’re doing. </p>

<p>You might feel that you are not really in charge of your life. </p>

<p>You might feel that you can’t  really remember things truly. </p>

<p>Like nothing becomes a memorable experience. </p>

<p>You have no time for metacognition and self-awareness. </p>

<p>I wrote these lines before finding out about this book <a href="http://www.carlhonore.com/books/in-praise-of-slowness/" title="In Praise of Slow | Carl Honoré">In Praise of Slow by Carl Honoré.</a> It seems this has inspired the slow-movement which tries to raise awareness of how we need to take it easy and enjoy life. Like the saying goes, <a href="http://mobile.brainyquote.com/quotes/quotes/m/maewest163658.html" title="Anything worth doing is worth doing slowly. - Mae West at BrainyQuote Mobile">anything worth doing is worth doing slowly.</a></p>

<p>It seems I have a new book to read. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On (re)learning things]]></title>
    <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2015/01/29/on-relearning-things/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-29T22:47:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2015/01/29/on-relearning-things</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>My favorite topic in an introductory differential equations course is mechanical and electrical vibrations. I enjoyed learning about it as a student and I enjoyed teaching it later. (Or more accurately, I enjoyed being exposed to it as a student and really learning it later when I had to teach it.)</p>

  <p>John D. Cook on <a href="http://www.johndcook.com/blog/2013/02/19/mechanical-vibrations/">Mechanical vibrations</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>I’ve always thought that education is about learning, as much as parenting is about maturing and growing up. On the parenting side, you can’t really teach your kids how to live – <a href="http://www.radiolab.org/story/288746-future-cant-control/" title="A Future You Can't Control - Radiolab">you can’t even imagine the kind of world they will have to live from the time they’re born</a> – but you <em>can</em> expose them to the best things you know. In doing so, they can at least have the chance to form an opinion on the many matters of life, they’ll surely make mistakes, but I bet they won’t regret much. </p>

<p>Education is a difficult topic. Everyone has something to say about it, yet no one seems to have true answers. I do think that education is much more about being exposed to something, rather than being taught that something. There’s an incredible difference between the two things.  </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not Collapsing the Wave Function]]></title>
    <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2014/01/31/not-collapsing-the-wave-function/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-31T09:32:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2014/01/31/not-collapsing-the-wave-function</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today in <a href="http://www.thisamericanlife.org/radio-archives/episode/399/contents-unknown" title="Contents Unknown | This American Life">“This American Life”</a> I was listening to an episode about hidden truths. It was really interesting to find out about a secret letter that the prime minister of Britain writes to every commander of a nuclear submarine. It supposedly contains instructions on what to do if the nation has been wiped out and if the commander should retaliate or not. It poses a mystery on what the contents are, even more so because every time there’s a new prime minister in office the letters are destroyed unread.</p>

<p>There are many questions that come about in knowing what the contents of the letter are. But to my understanding it is a way of reassuring your people that both possibilities exist. To retaliate or not. It is like delaying the final call on a difficult decision. Something akin to a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schrodinger_cat" title="Schrödinger's cat - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia">Schrödinger cat situation</a>.  </p>

<p>I’ve thought of this for while and I’ve come to understand that many people actually <em>like</em> to live their lives this way. Not wanting to know certain things, or more precisely clinging to the hope that a certain aspect in one’s life does not turn out to be what we fear so much. Keeping both options open (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wave_function" title="Wave function - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia"><em>not collapsing the wave function</em></a>) is probably a reassuring situation, relieving anxiety and allowing one to continue living unmoved by the cold hard reality. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ The Perils of Talking Too Much]]></title>
    <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2013/06/10/the-perils-of-talking-too-much/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-10T22:07:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2013/06/10/the-perils-of-talking-too-much</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="aic" style="width:500px"><img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/5279729/blog-pics/medium_5731336614.jpg" alt="" /><br />
photo credit: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/mkorsakov/5731336614/">mkorsakov</a> via <a href="http://photopin.com">photopin</a> <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/">cc</a></div>

<p>All too often I see people who simply talk too much.<sup id="fnref:fn1"><a href="#fn:fn1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> Wether what they speak is nonsense or <em>even</em> meaningful things, there’s a limit to how much one can tolerate. </p>

<p>By talking too much –  and too often – we miss out on many things. We don’t let others speak (which to my understanding is common courtesy), and worse of all we lose our capacity to empathize with others. We can’t <em>read faces</em> well while uttering words out of our mouths continuously. Loosing that feedback is what prompts us to speak without pause and with no care for what the people around us may feel. It’s what turns you into a prick. We’re just <em>too</em> focused on ourselves to care about others. </p>

<!-- more -->

<p>Having no feedback at all is dangerous, it really is. You tend to get the feeling that you’re always right. Usually, people are too polite to interrupt you and <a href="http://contentmarketingsuite.com/actionbar/15826/Are-You-A-Power-Poisoned-Boss" title="Are You A Power-Poisoned Boss?">bring you down a notch</a> and say, <em>it takes two to converse! This is no lecture</em>. A conversation is about sharing <a href="http://www.martynemko.com/articles/do-you-talk-too-much_id1371" title="Do You Talk Too Much?">and paying attention to your conversation partner’s needs.</a></p>

<p>It is no surprise that by talking too much we may alienate our loved ones and friends from our lives. They’ll avoid us and our utterances at all times. It is this kind of behavior that we have to be  careful about.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:fn1">
      <p>I used to be one of those, I know better now. <a href="#fnref:fn1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
