<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[andres marrugo]]></title>
  <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-19T21:25:54-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andres Marrugo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A CV for my Thesis]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2014/06/19/a-cv-for-my-thesis/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-19T21:11:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2014/06/19/a-cv-for-my-thesis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="aic" style="width:460px"><br />
<img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/5279729/blog-pics/IMG_0775.jpg" alt="" width="460" height="" border="0" /></div>

<p>A Ph.D. thesis is one of those things that has a life of its own. Last January, I had the opportunity to write a two-page abstract of my thesis for publication in <em>Electronic Letters on Computer Vision and Image Analysis</em>. It has been published and is now <a href="http://elcvia.cvc.uab.es/article/view/597" title="Retinal Image Analysis Oriented to the Clinical Task - Marrugo - Electronic Letters on Computer Vision and Image Analysis">available on the web along with the PhD thesis.</a></p>

<p>The paper is only a glimpse of all the hard work that went into the making of the thesis, but anyone who reads it may get a decent idea of what it is about, and where to find the results I’ve published in different journals. I don’t think anyone wants to go through the process of writing a thesis twice, but most will agree that it is a life changing experience. Many of the best moments of my life so far, happened while working towards the PhD, especially the birth of my two boys. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not Collapsing the Wave Function]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2014/01/31/not-collapsing-the-wave-function/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-31T09:32:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2014/01/31/not-collapsing-the-wave-function</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today in <a href="http://www.thisamericanlife.org/radio-archives/episode/399/contents-unknown" title="Contents Unknown | This American Life">“This American Life”</a> I was listening to an episode about hidden truths. It was really interesting to find out about a secret letter that the prime minister of Britain writes to every commander of a nuclear submarine. It supposedly contains instructions on what to do if the nation has been wiped out and if the commander should retaliate or not. It poses a mystery on what the contents are, even more so because every time there’s a new prime minister in office the letters are destroyed unread.</p>

<p>There are many questions that come about in knowing what the contents of the letter are. But to my understanding it is a way of reassuring your people that both possibilities exist. To retaliate or not. It is like delaying the final call on a difficult decision. Something akin to a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schrodinger_cat" title="Schrödinger's cat - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia">Schrödinger cat situation</a>.  </p>

<p>I’ve thought of this for while and I’ve come to understand that many people actually <em>like</em> to live their lives this way. Not wanting to know certain things, or more precisely clinging to the hope that a certain aspect in one’s life does not turn out to be what we fear so much. Keeping both options open (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wave_function" title="Wave function - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia"><em>not collapsing the wave function</em></a>) is probably a reassuring situation, relieving anxiety and allowing one to continue living unmoved by the cold hard reality. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ The Perils of Talking Too Much]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2013/06/10/the-perils-of-talking-too-much/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-10T22:07:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2013/06/10/the-perils-of-talking-too-much</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="aic" style="width:500px"><img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/5279729/blog-pics/medium_5731336614.jpg" alt="" /><br />
photo credit: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/mkorsakov/5731336614/">mkorsakov</a> via <a href="http://photopin.com">photopin</a> <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/">cc</a></div>

<p>All too often I see people who simply talk too much.<sup id="fnref:fn1"><a href="#fn:fn1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> Wether what they speak is nonsense or <em>even</em> meaningful things, there’s a limit to how much one can tolerate. </p>

<p>By talking too much –  and too often – we miss out on many things. We don’t let others speak (which to my understanding is common courtesy), and worse of all we lose our capacity to empathize with others. We can’t <em>read faces</em> well while uttering words out of our mouths continuously. Loosing that feedback is what prompts us to speak without pause and with no care for what the people around us may feel. It’s what turns you into a prick. We’re just <em>too</em> focused on ourselves to care about others. </p>

<!-- more -->

<p>Having no feedback at all is dangerous, it really is. You tend to get the feeling that you’re always right. Usually, people are too polite to interrupt you and <a href="http://contentmarketingsuite.com/actionbar/15826/Are-You-A-Power-Poisoned-Boss" title="Are You A Power-Poisoned Boss?">bring you down a notch</a> and say, <em>it takes two to converse! This is no lecture</em>. A conversation is about sharing <a href="http://www.martynemko.com/articles/do-you-talk-too-much_id1371" title="Do You Talk Too Much?">and paying attention to your conversation partner’s needs.</a></p>

<p>It is no surprise that by talking too much we may alienate our loved ones and friends from our lives. They’ll avoid us and our utterances at all times. It is this kind of behavior that we have to be  careful about.</p>

<div class="footnotes"><hr>
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:fn1">
      <p>I used to be one of those, I know better now. <a href="#fnref:fn1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Secularism]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2013/04/10/new-secularism/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-10T11:48:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2013/04/10/new-secularism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="aic" style="width:500px"><img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/5279729/blog-pics/medium_2911020311.jpg" alt="" /><br />
photo credit: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pablomoroe/2911020311/">Pablo Moroe</a> via <a href="http://photopin.com">photopin</a> <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/">cc</a>.</div>

<p>Before Darwin it certainly was <a href="http://choiceindying.com/2011/03/02/could-you-be-an-intellectually-fulfilled-atheist-before-darwin/" title="Could you be an intellectually fulfilled atheist before Darwin? | Choice in Dying">very difficult to be an atheist</a> or a nonbeliever – that is, an intellectually fulfilled one.<sup id="fnref:fn1"><a href="#fn:fn1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> At least that’s how <a href="http://www.talkorigins.org/indexcc/CA/CA602_1.html" title="CA602.1: An intellectually fulfilled atheist">Richard Dawkins</a> usually puts it and I quite agree with him. It was not that the scientific method<sup id="fnref:fn2"><a href="#fn:fn2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> didn’t exist at the time, it was that the mystery of life was too big a mystery to even consider tackling through the ways of science. Yet that was what Darwin did. </p>

<p>The topic of this post does not have to do with Darwin, at least in a direct sense. The other day I was listening to <a href="http://www.pointofinquiry.org/" title="Point of Inquiry">Point of Inquiry</a>, a podcast from the center of inquiry.<sup id="fnref:fn5"><a href="#fn:fn5" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> They had <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frans_de_Waal" title="Frans de Waal - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia">Frans de Waal</a> on and he talked about his latest book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Bonobo-Atheist-Humanism-ebook/dp/B007Q6XKEY"><em>The Bonobo and the Atheist</em></a>. There was a moment during the interview that the host, Chris Mooney, referred to him as being an atheist to which he replied saying </p>

<!-- more -->

<blockquote>
  <p>I am not necessarily an [atheist], because atheism has now come to stand for being very strongly opposed to religion which is really not what I am, I prefer to call my self either a <em>nonbeliever</em> or an <em>apathetic</em> meaning that, the agnostic doesn’t know if god exists, the atheist denies the existence of god, and <em>I basically don’t care</em>. I don’t think it is an important or interesting problem to discuss god. And as a scientist, I don’t know what to do with the god question. It will never be resolved, certainly not by science. </p>

  <p><strong>– Frans de Waal</strong>, On <a href="http://www.pointofinquiry.org/frans_de_waal_the_bonobo_and_the_atheist/">Point of Inquiry: Frans de Waal - The Bonobo and the Atheist</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>I can truly relate to his words. As much as I identify with people like Richard Dawkins or Sam Harris, being an atheist does not have to mean being opposed to religion. I can do that without being one. As a matter of fact religion and the institutions that promote it have done so much wrong to mankind that the logic behind them falls apart rather quickly. </p>

<p>What I can’t seem to get around my head is that despite that, religion is still a creation of humans and if I want to take the scientist’s approach I should accept it for what it is. That doesn’t mean, like de Wall suggests, that it cannot be replaced with something else. In his book, he argues that morality is something that is older than our species. Research suggests that many primates, and other animals, have a sense of morality. Meaning that they have impulses and self control mechanisms to resolve conflicts, to determine rules, etc. </p>

<p>In fact <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massimo_Pigliucci" title="Massimo Pigliucci - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia">Massimo Pigliucci’s</a> book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Answers-Aristotle-Science-Philosophy-Meaningful/dp/0465021387"><em>Answers for Aristotle</em></a> attempts to solve that problem by saying that we should lead a life that is both philosophically and scientifically pertinent. Going back to the whole being opposed to religion issue, I say, denying god gets us nowhere. The existentialist questions still remain and it says nothing about what’s the best way to lead a life. Our society is too big and complex to pretend that we shouldn’t pursue such questions. However, we should use the best tools we’ve got for the job, and in the twenty-first century these are not religion or theology. </p>

<p>To conclude I would like to say that we shouldn’t really attack religion for what it is or for being wrong, we should instead try to show the way with the best tools we have. Resolving conflict without invoking god. Discussing real life issues with the best evidence we can find. Addressing our questions knowing wholeheartedly our limits. </p>

<div class="footnotes"><hr>
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:fn1">
      <p>Yes, before Darwin we had <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Hume">David Hume</a>, but his reasoning was solely based on the fact that <a href="http://choiceindying.com/2011/03/02/could-you-be-an-intellectually-fulfilled-atheist-before-darwin/" title="Could you be an intellectually fulfilled atheist before Darwin? | Choice in Dying">God isn’t a good explanation</a> for biological design. It was Darwin who came up with one.<a href="#fnref:fn1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:fn2">
      <p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_scientific_method#Galileo_Galilei" title="History of scientific method - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia">Galileo Galilei</a> is often referred to as the father of the scientific method. <a href="#fnref:fn2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:fn5">
      <p>“A think tank promoting science, reason, and secular values in public policy and at the grass roots”.<a href="#fnref:fn5" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Book for my Son]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2013/03/27/a-book-for-my-son/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-27T21:21:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2013/03/27/a-book-for-my-son</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the latest <a href="http://www.70decibels.com/generational/2013/3/24/027-aaron-hillegass-and-teaching-experts.html" title="70Decibels - Generational - 027 - Aaron Hillegass and Teaching Experts">Generational podcast</a> episode <a href="http://www.bignerdranch.com/instructors/hillegass.shtml">Aaron Hillegass</a> told <a href="http://www.macdrifter.com/" title="Macdrifter">Gabe</a> that he wrote his <a href="http://www.bignerdranch.com/book/objective-c_programming_the_big_nerd_ranch_guide">Objective-C</a> book with his ten-year-old in mind. </p>

<p>I found this to be quite interesting and truly inspiring. By writing the book “for his son,” he made sure anyone could actually read and understand it, but also he was deeply motivated to get it right. I wouldn’t want my son to read a crappy book. </p>

<p>If I ever had to write a guide about how to be (stay) motivated on a project this would definitely be there.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Brave New World: The joy of discovery]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2013/03/10/a-brave-new-world/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-10T21:44:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2013/03/10/a-brave-new-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This post is in fact a <a href="http://dayoneapp.com/">Day One</a> entry. I treat my Day One journal as a sort of personal blog. A blog with a readership of one – at least in the present. What I mean to say is that, for the most part, I write about my life and for my kids, which are too young to read. I hope they read this in some distant future. I think that the things I might forget are probably the things they’ll want to know about. That is why I write.</em></p>

<!--more-->

<p><em>Occasionally I like to share and entry with my wife, which now Day One makes it so easy by offering the export to PDF option (<a href="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/5279729/blog-pics/Screenshot%202013-03-10%20at%2008.49.51.png">click here</a> to see what the pdf looks like). Day One is an awesome app which inevitably has made me write more, reflect upon my thoughts and experiences both personal and with the people close to me. It has enabled something which I had lost, having conversations with myself, past and present, which I believe is part of being and feeling alive.</em></p>

<hr />

<p>I’ve been trying to teach Alejandro how to go down the stairs for several months now. For the most part it’s been an unfruitful endeavor, and not because he doesn’t want to go down the stairs; quite the contrary. He loves going down (or trying to go down) but walking right up on his two feet, like he sees everyone else doing it. </p>

<p>Just about every time I tried to show him how to slide his little butt, step by step, to go down safely, he would hurry down the stairs unafraid of falling. After a couple of months of no progress whatsoever I gave up, he can crawl up the stairs, but to go down I have to grab him while he pretends to go down like a grown-up. </p>

<p>Today that was different. I took him out to a nearby park so he could play outside in the sun. After riding his tricycle for about ten minutes he started to wander about in the park. Most of the times he wanders erratically, like going with the flow; chasing whatever is in his sight: a pigeon, a rock, a ball or another kid. </p>

<p>After a while he began to play going up and – with my help – down some stairs in the park. For him it was quite fun, for me a bit stressing because he can’t quite sense the danger in playing around stairs. </p>

<p>After several tries he – out of pure accident – stumbled upon a solution to go down the stairs in a fairly safe way. Sliding on his buttocks. He doesn’t speak yet, however I could sense in his eyes the satisfaction for having made a significant discovery, another way of doing things not known to him before. </p>

<p>I’m not making an argument for implying that he has a deep thought process like an adult, I know he doesn’t. Yet that feeling of true discovery was as vivid in his eyes as I see it in adults. I would say it is even more powerful, because he doesn’t  feel shame in expressing his feelings. He has no reason whatsoever to hide his ignorance. His discovery is genuine, as are his feelings. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links of Interest for January 31, 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2013/01/31/links-of-interest/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2013/01/31/links-of-interest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/categories/bookmarks/">“Links of Interest”</a> is a type of post I’ll start to do on a regular basis here. Every now and then I come across something interesting in the web that I’d like to share with my readers, but that doesn’t necessarily merit a blog post or I really don’t have the time to write one. This type of blog post is inspired by <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/2013/01/15/a-web-excursions-system-for-static-blogs/" title="A &quot;Web Excursions&quot; system for static blogs - Brett Terpstra">Brett Terpstra’s “Web Excursions”</a> system. As he explains, he prefers a single post with multiple links rather than a ton of individual “link list” posts. I do too.</p>

<p>To find out more about the details and the ruby script for automatically generating the post <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/2013/01/15/a-web-excursions-system-for-static-blogs/" title="A &quot;Web Excursions&quot; system for static blogs - Brett Terpstra">go to his website</a>. The links posted here, I’ve gathered in the past couple of weeks using <a href="http://pinboard.in/">pinboard</a> an incredibly useful bookmarking service. Enjoy.</p>

<!-- more -->

<h2 id="the-links">The links</h2>

<dl>
  <dt><a href="http://www.wikiwebapp.com/">Wikiweb - A Delightful Wikipedia Reader</a></dt>
  <dd>The power of wiki backlinks. Visualizing connections between articles.   </dd>
  <dt><a href="http://cvip.computing.dundee.ac.uk/papers/TruccoIOVS2013inpress.pdf">Validating Retinal Fundus Image Analysis Algorithms: Issues And A Proposal</a></dt>
  <dd>Interesting article in which the “big players” in the field of retinal image analysis make recommendations on the possible avenues for research. The purpose is that the research may have a greater impact on the clinical practice.    </dd>
  <dt><a href="http://dictionary2.classic.reference.com/writing/styleguide/footnotes.html">Footnotes, Endnotes and Textnotes</a></dt>
  <dd>A brief style-guide on the use of footnotes, and the like. I came to this page by looking up the recommended style for placing superscript of footnotes next to punctuation marks. BTW it should always go after the punctuation mark, unless the mark is a dash.   </dd>
  <dt><a href="http://www.seankorzdorfer.com/open_notebook/voodoopad%20workflow%20and%20notes.html#section-why">VoodooPad Workflow and Notes</a></dt>
  <dd>Sean Korzdorfer’s workflow on note-taking and using a personal wiki. Really cool.</dd>
  <dt><a href="http://blog.xkoder.com/2008/08/13/git-tutorial-starting-with-git-using-just-10-commands/">xk0der » Git Tutorial : Starting with git using just 10 commands</a></dt>
  <dd>A basic tutorial on git version control.</dd>
  <dt><a href="http://talmai-oliveira.blogspot.com.es/2011/06/how-to-cite-matlab-bibtex-latex.html">Things I Shouldn’t Forget: How to cite MATLAB (bibtex / latex)</a></dt>
  <dd>Truly important. How to cite the all powerful MATLAB.</dd>
  <dt><a href="http://mattgemmell.com/2013/01/15/writing-tools/">Writing Tools - Matt Gemmell</a></dt>
  <dd>Matt Gemmell gives a nice overview of the tools he uses to write plus some general advice on avoiding writer’s block and getting stuff done.</dd>
  <dt><a href="http://www.chocomoko.com/brisk">Brisk</a></dt>
  <dd>An interesting alternative to LaTeXiT on the mac. Doesn’t need a latex installation. </dd>
  <dt><a href="https://medium.com/the-writers-room/8d6e7df7ae58">The Spark File — The Writer’s Room — Medium</a></dt>
  <dd>A “spark” file for writing down anything that goes through your mind. Later revisiting it to find  reminders of useful ideas.  </dd>
  <dt><a href="http://www.cs.berkeley.edu/~jrs/speaking.html">Giving an Academic Talk</a></dt>
  <dd>A nice article on general guidelines and tips for giving a “decent” academic presentation.</dd>
  <dt><a href="http://www.idryman.org/blog/2012/03/10/writing-math-equations-on-octopress/">Writing math equations on Octopress</a></dt>
  <dd>A nice little tutorial on posting LaTeX equations on Octopress.</dd>
  <dt><a href="http://bigthink.com/rewire/a-tech-geek-on-why-we-need-the-humanities">A Tech Geek on Why We Need the Humanities | Input/Output | Big Think</a></dt>
  <dd>A nice piece on the importance of arts alongside technology. Because “the only jobs left to humans in the not-so-distant future will be those that computers can’t do – the kind that demand intuition and creative thinking.”</dd>
  <dt><a href="http://www.elezea.com/2012/12/do-what-you-love/">How to do what you love, the right way</a></dt>
  <dd>A call to forget about titles and do “what you love.”</dd>
  <dt><a href="https://medium.com/i-m-h-o/52a20d7a17de">Why I love Twitter and barely tolerate Facebook — I.M.H.O. — Medium</a></dt>
  <dd>MATT HAUGHEY explains his reasons for liking so much twitter and barely tolerating Facebook. In his words, twitter is the now, is the present. You follow people more for what they have to say, rather than for how they relate to you (high school friend, attended the same university, etc).  Facebook is all about the past.  </dd>
</dl>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Writing my thoughts down]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2013/01/02/writing-my-thoughts-down/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-02T22:52:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2013/01/02/writing-my-thoughts-down</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="aic" style="width:500px"><img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/5279729/blog-pics/medium_3989921751.jpg" alt="iPod touch" /><br />
photo credit: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/chiarashine/3989921751/">chiarashine</a> via <a href="http://photopin.com">photopin</a> <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/">cc</a></div>

<p>As is often the case, ideas come about in the most unexpected moments. Lately, I’ve found myself taking notes while walking to work, while waiting for a coffee in front of a bending machine, or like now while getting dressed for work. </p>

<p>It’s become a habit of mine to write what I think, when I think it. My iPod touch has enabled that. I could well have pen and paper with me at all times, but I’m not used to that and nothing beats the digital format. </p>

<!--more-->

<p>I journal much more now than ever before, and that’s thanks to apps like <a href="http://dayoneapp.com/" title="Day One | A simple Journal for iPhone, iPad and Mac App Store">Day One</a> or <a href="http://agiletortoise.com/drafts" title="Drafts - Agile Tortoise">Drafts</a>. Writing  my thoughts down has never been easier. And, to tell you the truth, it’s <em>liberating</em>. It’s like <a href="http://5by5.tv/b2w/96" title="5by5 | Back to Work #96: Compensatory Muscles">Merlin Mann</a> says, “your brain has permission to think at all times.” And, as Melissa Donovan says in her book <a href="http://amzn.com/0615547850">101 Creative Writing Exercises</a>, “Journaling…promotes observation, self-awareness, and reflection, all skills that great writers must possess”, (by way of <a href="http://writeitsideways.com/learning-to-see-the-good-in-bad-writing/" title="Learning to See the Good in Bad Writing">Christi Craig</a>). My journaling has come a long way since I started using <a href="http://dayoneapp.com/" title="Day One | A simple Journal for iPhone, iPad and Mac App Store">Day One</a> last year. Some blog posts start there, or even certain personal emails too. Journaling helps me to reflect upon my thoughts and to make important decisions. </p>

<p>I’ve always been fond of writing, yet I’ve never had such an intimate relationship with my thoughts and my inner self. I believe that writing brings about the best in me. Through writing I can look at my human face and recognize my afflictions and ghosts. </p>

<p>Even as I sit here on my bed, tying my shoelaces, I feel an urge to get my thoughts out. I had never experienced this strong desire before. I, however, am totally aware that the more I write, the more I feel this urge. It’s quite fascinating and at times I just can’t help myself. </p>

<p>Happy new year to all my readers. Hope you had a nice time during the holidays and that you soon start your 2013 projects motivated and committed to getting things done – at least that’s my main purpose for this year.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Careless email writing]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/12/26/careless-email-writing/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-26T10:16:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/12/26/careless-email-writing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="aic" style="width:500px"><img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/5279729/blog-pics/medium_2756494307.jpg" alt="Text editing." /><br />
photo credit: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/nicmcphee/2756494307/">Unhindered by Talent</a> via <a href="http://photopin.com">photopin</a> <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/">cc</a></div>

<p>I read the other day an email that desperately needed some editing. Writing without editing is pretty much the same as speaking with little attention to what we are saying. The great advantage of the <em>written form</em> over the spoken one is that you <em>can</em> go back an edit. Not editing what you write is both a poor use of the written form and a sign that you don’t care much for the person that will read your message. </p>

<!--more-->

<p>It’s not that a typo is not allowed, no one is perfect. But to write something without punctuation is just insane. All too often I hear people say that, because they are not writers or journalists they are somehow excused of writing poorly. I think it is just plain laziness. It’s a laziness that reads as our lack of interest for a craft so important to us by which we express what we feel and think.</p>

<p>How is it, that common sense doesn’t rouse in these situations? Why is it so difficult to realize that a 500+ word email written in a single paragraph without punctuation is just <em>illegible</em>. It costs so much to get the ideas out of that mess. The laziness to which I refer does service to no one, and buries even the meaning of your well-intended message.</p>

<p>So do yourself a favor and go back and edit the message a bit before hitting the send button.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA['Cooking' Ideas]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/12/07/cooking-ideas/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-07T21:02:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/12/07/cooking-ideas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love to cook – or one of the reasons I enjoy it so much is – because it’s a manual activity that, quite often, lets my mind wonder about. While cooking I can think about my problems,<sup id="fnref:fn1"><a href="#fn:fn1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> about the future, about a world different from this one. I can hear my thoughts in a undisturbed way. It is like a moment of pristine inspiration. Me and myself. Nobody else.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>I seldom write those thoughts down, because – well, it’s quite obvious – I’m cooking at the moment and if I did that, dinner would take forever to be ready. </p>

<p>So, as beautiful and inspiring the whole while-cooking thought process may be, it is <em>ephemeral</em>. As soon as dinner is ready I get back to the current issue and most of what was in my mind, just moments ago, vanishes – or so it seems. I think that on a subconscious level those thoughts do stick around. </p>

<p>What I certainly don’t like about cooking is the planning itself. If I want to cook chicken in the evening, and it’s in the fridge I have to remind myself to take it out in the morning – which quite often means I have to plan it the day before. And let’s be honest, having to think about getting chicken out of the fridge is not exactly the most intellectual thing one could be doing – yet, it’s got to happen and someone’s got to do it. </p>

<p>Except for that, cooking (to me) is quite a satisfactory experience which enables me to  enjoy myself and have an encounter with my thoughts and imagination. It’s (almost) like  day dreaming, but it’s not. It’s much more. </p>

<div class="footnotes"><hr>
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:fn1">
      <p>It’s something of a coincidence, but there’s a great <a href="http://macpowerusers.com/" title="Mac Power Users">mac power users</a> episode called <a href="http://macpowerusers.com/2012/04/mpu-082-cooking-ideas/" title="MPU 082: Cooking Ideas « Mac Power Users">“cooking ideas”</a>, where David and Katie cover strategies for using mindmapping and outlining tools. I highly recommend it.<a href="#fnref:fn1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ My reflection in a mirror of prose]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/11/16/my-reflection-in-a-mirror-of-prose/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-16T07:02:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/11/16/my-reflection-in-a-mirror-of-prose</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I like to write, for writing reminds me of who I am, who I want to be, and where I come from. It is no mistery that I enjoy it, but that doesn’t make it any easier. </p>

<p>I often get compliments on my writing, but still, I think there’s a long way to go before I feel more comfortable with it – I still struggle over single words or sentences. </p>

<p>Lately, I’ve been rediscovering myself in many different ways. I find myself more aware of everything – and that is probably not the most interesting thing – if not by chance, by fate, but I do feel different. I certainly am not the same person I was a while ago. I write more, which means <em>I exit my body more often</em>. </p>

<!--more-->

<p>I write about my writing, for it serves as confession and a means to <em>see</em> my reflection in a mirror of prose. A reflection of what I think, and of who I am. It is no coincidence that by writing I often find answers to my problems or get a glance of the next step I should take. </p>

<p>Writing is <em>almost</em> certainly  not for everyone, at least in the sense of writing for the fun of it. I hardly know people – in person that is<sup id="fnref:fn1"><a href="#fn:fn1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> – that write out of pure pleasure, let alone people that <em>truly</em> make a living out of writing. </p>

<p>Writing is an art, but is also a skill. A skill that – despite natural talent – requires time and effort in developing. Like <a href="http://www.mcsweeneys.net/authors/colin-nissan">Colin Nissan</a> says in the <a href="http://www.mcsweeneys.net/articles/the-ultimate-guide-to-writing-better-than-you-normally-do">“Ultimate guide to writing better than you normally do”</a></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Writing is a muscle. Smaller than a hamstring and slightly bigger than a bicep, and it needs to be exercised to get stronger. Think of your words as reps, your paragraphs as sets, your pages as daily workouts. Think of your laptop as a machine like the one at the gym where you open and close your inner thighs in front of everyone, exposing both your insecurities and your genitals. Because that is what writing is all about.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Yes, it’s about exposing yourself and becoming stronger in the process. </p>

<div class="footnotes"><hr>
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:fn1">
      <p>In the <em>virtual</em> world, I <em>do</em> know a number of people that write for the fun of it and are lucky enough to make a living from it. <a href="#fnref:fn1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Four Paragraphs Long]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/11/02/four-paragraphs-long/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-02T23:37:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/11/02/four-paragraphs-long</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I don’t really know what this post is about or even why I decided it should be blog post in the first place. All I can think is that  I really liked it. I thought it would be interesting to share it with others. Not that it would be useful or anything, simply a pleasant read. </p>

<p>It’s not meant to mean anything in particular – at least in any philosophical way. It’s just something I conjured up the other day before going to bed. After I read it a couple of times, I knew it was a true gem. Only four paragraphs long, yet so deep with frustration and love. The love of a father towards his son, and of those little – apparently insignificant – moments that stick with you for the rest of your life. Here it is.</p>

<h2 id="a-very-short-midnight-story">A <em>very</em> short midnight story</h2>

<p><em>It’s almost midnight and I can’t really prevent my eyes from closing. I’m tired as hell, yet I can’t seem to convince myself into the idea that I should get some sleep.</em> </p>

<p><em>I don’t have a big day tomorrow or anything, it’s just that my kid wakes up so goddamn early. Well, that’s what he’s supposed to do, and I can’t find an argument against that – at least a plausible one.</em></p>

<p><em>Sometimes he just stays awake, lying there in my regular-sized bed, staring at me directly into my eyes, even though I have them closed, like waiting for the slightest  hint of evidence that I too, am awake.</em></p>

<p><em>At the first sight of a blink, he launches himself toward me. “Papa, papa,” he shouts with excitement. I open my eyes wide, he sticks his finger in one of them – it hurts.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Always Late to The Party]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/22/always-late-to-the-party/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-22T00:11:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/22/always-late-to-the-party</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="to-tweet-or-not-to-tweet">To Tweet or Not to Tweet</h2>

<p>It always seems I’m late to the party. For several years I pondered on the idea of joining <a href="https://twitter.com/" title="Twitter">Twitter</a>, but it never really made much sense to me – at least at the time – to join a social network where there were hardly any friends of mine<sup id="fnref:fn1"><a href="#fn:fn1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>. Big mistake, that actually <em>is</em> one of the cool things about twitter. Unlike Facebook, it <em>does</em> provides an open space suitable for engaging in discussions, albeit short, of all sorts with interesting people who don’t really have to be your “friend.”</p>

<p>It turns out that shortly after joining twitter most people<sup id="fnref:fn2"><a href="#fn:fn2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> were already considering abandoning it in favor of <a href="https://join.app.net/" title="Join the Movement - App.net">App.net</a>. For the time being <a href="https://join.app.net/" title="Join the Movement - App.net">App.net</a> seems like a <em>niche</em> thing, and most people seem to continue on twitter. Whether that stays that way for the next year or so depends on twitter and their recent policy changes that could well endanger the platform as we know it today. </p>

<!--more-->

<h2 id="its-all-about-the-editor">It’s All About The Editor</h2>

<p>For quite a while it seemed that everywhere I looked, geeks where rejoicing and feeling proud of their text editor of choice: <a href="http://macromates.com/" title="TextMate — The Missing Editor for Mac OS X">Textmate</a>. I did look into it a couple of times, but I always thought it ways a bit too expensive for me. </p>

<p>For the most part it seemed I had always managed to get by with the tools at my disposal, I really didn’t feel like I needed something else.
I would use the builtin Matlab editor for writing Matlab code. As regards LaTeX – for writing papers – I would use the open source and free (as in beer) <a href="http://www.xm1math.net/texmaker/" title="Texmaker (free cross-platform latex editor)">Texmaker</a>. I really wasn’t aware of the exciting and cool features of <em>advanced</em> text editors like Textmate or <a href="http://www.vim.org/" title="welcome home : vim online">Vim</a>. </p>

<p>For as long as I can remember, I’ve been a computer enthusiast, but a lone one. I never did have close friends that were into the sort of things I liked. I was never really ostracized, but I <em>was</em> the “nerd” nevertheless. </p>

<p>This brief digression is not without a purpose, which is to bring forth the fact that despite being a geek, I’ve never been part of a geek community of any sort. And this influenced my way of life and how I – before social networks – ended up finding out about the latest and coolest thing. More often than not, late and when it wasn’t really a <em>new</em> thing. The text editor dilemma is proof to my lack of geeky-social interaction.</p>

<p>Before I bought Textmate, I <em>did</em> do a little background check to see what was happening to its development. Apparently it was being not-so-actively developed, but version 2.0 was on the way. I had managed to somehow convince myself that it was totally worth it and that I would write my thesis with it. </p>

<p>Shortly after I bought it, it went open source, and to the impression of some: abandoned. It seems that for quite some time, everyone had been moving to Sublime text or BBEdit. Late to the party once again. I just can’t stop thinking that if somehow I had looked into it a bit more, if I had participated more on forums and different communities all of this would have ended differently. I <em>can</em> however say, that I am still using Textmate 1,  and I’m enjoying my self quite a bit.</p>

<h2 id="a-static-or-dynamic-blog">A Static or Dynamic Blog</h2>

<p>Technically speaking I’ve been bloggin since 2010. However, I must be honest and admit that for about the first year of my <a href="http://copiancestral.wordpress.com/" title="Between the Candle and the Star | Academia, Computing, and other topics.">(former) blog</a> I hardly posted a thing or two. It was a <a href="http://wordpress.com/" title="WordPress.com — Get a Free Blog Here">wordpress.com</a> blog and for nearly the last year or so, I began posting more regularly and I was really enjoying myself. I rapidly got accustomed to wordpress; so much, that I felt trapped in the platform, and I needed more customization to set things my way. Well, for the looks of it, I had to leave wordpress.com and move my blog somewhere else in order to do just that.</p>

<p>I kept blogging there, while I looked around to explore my options. It was interesting that this time I was <em>also</em> late, but not so much in the sense that I was able to catch a lot of people during their <a href="http://www.macdrifter.com/migrating-to-pelican-extracting-wordpress-data.html" title="Migrating to Pelican - Extracting WordPress Data">migration from a dynamic blog to a static one</a>. I’m not going to go through the details of why I chose a static blog, but it does have its advantages with respect to a dynamic one, like wordpress. </p>

<h2 id="getting-stuff-done">Getting Stuff Done</h2>

<p>As a final section for this already long post, I’d like to mention how I’ve also been late to the whole GTD movement (if there is such a thing). It’s amusing how shortly after I started to actually read David Allen’s book on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Getting_Things_Done" title="Getting Things Done - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia">“Getting Things Done”</a>, some people were already arguing </p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“whether GTD [was] valid after more than 10 years without any real “update”.”</p>

  <p>– <strong>Sven Fechner</strong>, <a href="http://simplicitybliss.com/the-state-of-getting-things-done" title="The State of Getting Things Done — SimplicityBliss">The State of Getting Things Done.</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>I can’t really say for my self, if it is still valid. I can, however, say that it still seems to make sense in the philosophy behind it, probably not so much in the methodology. But hey, what can I say, I haven’t even finished the <em>goddamn</em> book.</p>

<p>I’ve been late, as always, to many fascinating events of recent years – at least the geeky ones it seems. But I’ve come to accept that as a reality of mine. These days I can say that I try to keep myself more in the loop by following several interesting people on the web, whether it be via their blogs, twitter, or podcasts. This  seems a bit of a remedy to my bad timing, but hey everyone’s entitled to do things their way. I’m still struggling to actually find what <em>is</em> “my way”, but I’m in no hurry. There probably isn’t any <em>real</em> answer, <a href="http://www.macdrifter.com/2012/08/fiddle-sticks.html" title="Fiddle Sticks">I reckon the search is more valuable than the goal itself.</a></p>

<div class="footnotes"><hr>
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:fn1">
      <p>I <em>still</em> have few close friends on twitter; most of them are rarely active. As regards Facebook, I cannot say the same. <a href="#fnref:fn1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:fn2">
      <p>When I say <em>most</em> people, I actually mean the majority of people worth following. <a href="#fnref:fn2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Convert Image to PDF with Automator and Imagemagick]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/18/image-to-pdf-with-automator-and-imagemagick/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-18T22:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/18/image-to-pdf-with-automator-and-imagemagick</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I often use <a href="http://www.imagemagick.org/script/index.php">Imagemagick</a> for image manipulation<sup id="fnref:fn2"><a href="#fn:fn2" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>. However, for simple conversion of an image to another format or similar things I have to go to the terminal and type something like the following</p>

<pre><code>convert somefile.png somefile.pdf
</code></pre>

<p>Which is quite simple, and much better than opening preview -&gt; export<sup id="fnref:fn1"><a href="#fn:fn1" rel="footnote">2</a></sup>-&gt;select pdf-&gt; and hit save. But typing that for more than one image is <em>also</em> tedious. So, I decided I’d better create a service that would essentially do the following.</p>

<p>It would take the selected finder items, mainly images in <code>png</code>, <code>jpeg</code>, or whatever, and convert all of them to <code>pdf</code>. Simple. <!--more-->  The automator service is shown in the following image. It does exactly what I’ve described.</p>

<div class="aic" style="width:500px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/8099954950/" title="to-pdf-automator-script by copiancestral, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8045/8099954950_8d97fab95f.jpg" width="500" height="252" alt="to-pdf-automator-script" /></a><br />
Automator service.</div>

<p>The shell script is quite simple. Because the <code>convert</code> command from Imagemagick is not a command in bash, I have to call it with the whole path. The rest of that one-liner is a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sed"><code>sed</code></a> call to substitute  whatever extension the input file has (with the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regular_expression" title="Regular expression - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia">regex</a> <code>\..*</code>) to <code>.pdf</code>, and that’s it. Here’s the script.</p>

<div class="bogus-wrapper"><notextile><figure class="code"><figcaption><span>convert-to-pdf   </span></figcaption>
 <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class="line-number">1</span>
<span class="line-number">2</span>
<span class="line-number">3</span>
<span class="line-number">4</span>
<span class="line-number">5</span>
</pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="bash"><span class="line"><span class="k">for </span>f in <span class="s2">&quot;$@&quot;</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="k">do</span>
</span><span class="line">  /opt/local/bin/convert <span class="s2">&quot;$f&quot;</span> <span class="sb">`</span><span class="nb">echo</span> <span class="s2">&quot;$f&quot;</span>|sed <span class="s2">&quot;s/\..*/.pdf/&quot;</span><span class="sb">`</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="k">done</span>
</span><span class="line">
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>

<div class="footnotes"><hr>
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:fn2">
      <p>As a matter of fact, now that I’ve finally upgraded to Mountain Lion, Imagemagick stopped working. Had to reinstall with macports.<a href="#fnref:fn2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:fn1">
      <p>“Save as” in the old days, prior to OS X 10.7.<a href="#fnref:fn1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My blog post writing workflow with Dropbox and Hazel]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/15/blog-post-writing-workflow-dropbox-hazel/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-15T23:44:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/15/blog-post-writing-workflow-dropbox-hazel</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It may seem that, for the most part, I’ve been blogging about blogging. No matter how pointless it seems, I <em>do</em> think that this could prove useful to someone, in the same way I have benefited from others while setting up this site<sup id="fnref:foo2"><a href="#fn:foo2" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>.</p>

<p>One of the things I like about having an <a href="http://octopress.org/" title="Octopress">Octopress</a> driven <code>txt</code>-only blog is that I have the liberty to set things my way. The topic I am addressing here is that of writing blog posts on different devices<sup id="fnref:foo1"><a href="#fn:foo1" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> with the help of Dropbox<sup id="fnref:foo5"><a href="#fn:foo5" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> and <a href="http://www.noodlesoft.com/hazel.php" title="Noodlesoft | Hazel">Hazel</a>. I’m still working out the whole remote blogging thing, this is but the first stage of a soon-to-be remote blogging workflow with Octopress. </p>

<!--more-->

<!-- When I say "different devices" I actually mean three:

- A Macbook Pro at the office, almost always on.
- A Mac Mini at home, often on, but not necessary logged in my user.
- An iPod Touch, always with me. -->

<h2 id="my-blog-post-writing-workflow">My blog post writing workflow</h2>

<p>Ideally any blog post starts with an idea that I write down in a text file named <code>runx-blog_ideas-qqq.txt</code><sup id="fnref:foo3"><a href="#fn:foo3" rel="footnote">4</a></sup>. This is done either on any of the two Macs using <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/project/nvalt/" title="nvALT 2.1 - Notational Velocity Fork">nvAlt</a> or on my iOS device using any text editor<sup id="fnref:foo4"><a href="#fn:foo4" rel="footnote">5</a></sup>. I <em>always</em> write in <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/" title="Daring Fireball: Markdown">Markdown</a> (technically I <em>mostly</em> write in <a href="http://fletcherpenney.net/multimarkdown/" title="MultiMarkdown">Multimarkdown</a>, but that’s another thing). </p>

<p>After I decide that this idea is ready to become a draft, I create a text file that follows the same name convention for Octopress (<code>2012-10-14-Post-title.text</code>) on a folder named <code>_drafts</code> that resides in the <code>source</code>. You might have noticed that the extension is not <code>.markdown</code> and that is because I was having issues <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/fixing-spotlight-indexing-of-markdown-content/" title="Fixing Spotlight indexing of Markdown content - Brett Terpstra">making Hazel read the contents of markdown files</a>. So I opted for <code>.text</code> which is technically the same as <code>.txt</code>, but I would differentiate them as drafts and most <em>importantly</em> <a href="http://macsparky.com/2009/6/3/sorting-and-moving-documents-with-hazel.html" title="Sorting and Moving Documents with Hazel — MacSparky">Hazel will be able to do its magic</a>.</p>

<p>The underscore (<code>_</code>) on the name of the drafts folder is so that it won’t be deployed, just as the posts folder</p>

<pre><code>source/
|__ _drafts/
|__ _posts/
</code></pre>

<p>With the help of <a href="http://www.ergonis.com/products/typinator/" title="Typinator - the fastest text expander in town">Typinator</a> on my mac or <a href="http://smilesoftware.com/TextExpander/touch/index.html" title="TextExpander touch: iOS Typing Shortcuts for iPhone and iPad">Textexpander</a> on my iPod I create the yaml header like this</p>

<pre><code>--- 
layout: post 
title: "Post title" 
date: 2012-10-14 23:28 
author: Andres Marrugo 
comments: true 
published: false 
categories: [blog] 
--- 
</code></pre>

<p>Notice that <code>published: false</code>, which means <em>it is a draft</em>. When I’m finished with the post I’ll change it to <code>true</code>. </p>

<h3 id="the-syncing">The Syncing</h3>

<p>The Syncing is done via Dropbox, because any iOS text editor comes with Dropbox support. iCloud has still a long way to go. Because my octopress folder does not reside in the Dropbox folder I made symlinks on my Mac to the <code>_posts</code>, <code>_drafts</code>, and <code>images</code> folders so they get synced </p>

<pre><code>ln -s ~/octopress/source/_posts/ ~/Dropbox/PlainText/blog/_posts
ln -s ~/octopress/source/images/ ~/Dropbox/blog/PlainText/images
ln -s ~/octopress/source/_drafts/ ~/Dropbox/blog/PlainText/_drafts
</code></pre>

<p>On any other machine they become actual folders.</p>

<h3 id="automating-with-hazel">Automating with Hazel</h3>

<p>Ideally I would like to change the <code>published: false</code> to <code>true</code> and have it posted to my site, but it still requires some workarounds and this is why for the time being my hazel magic script only moves the file to the <code>_posts</code> folder when the published option changes to <code>true</code>. I then generate the site and deploy it manually, but this will soon be automated as well.</p>

<p>There are actually two Hazel rules for this. It first monitors the <code>_drafts</code> folder for files whose content contains the phrase <code>published: true</code>. When this happens the file gets moved to the folder <code>_posts</code>.</p>

<div class="aic" style="width:500px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/7913589162/" title="drafts-move-to-posts-hazel by copiancestral, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8038/7913589162_551eed930a.jpg" width="500" height="243" alt="drafts-move-to-posts-hazel" /></a><br />
Move file to _posts folder.</div>

<p>Then the second rule is for the <code>_posts</code> folder. If the extension is <code>text</code> (which means it was a draft that recently got moved) it will run a shell script.</p>

<div class="aic" style="width:500px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/7913591478/" title="posts-modify-latest-post-hazel by copiancestral, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8458/7913591478_f75d933161.jpg" width="500" height="356" alt="posts-modify-latest-post-hazel" /></a><br />
Modify latest post.</div>

<p>The shell script is the following. What it does is to replace the date with the current date – you see, several days could’ve passed since I created the draft – in both the yaml header and the file name. And the other thing it does is to change the extension to <code>.markdown</code>.  </p>

<div class="bogus-wrapper"><notextile><figure class="code"><figcaption><span>Move to posts folder   </span></figcaption>
 <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class="line-number">1</span>
<span class="line-number">2</span>
<span class="line-number">3</span>
<span class="line-number">4</span>
<span class="line-number">5</span>
<span class="line-number">6</span>
<span class="line-number">7</span>
<span class="line-number">8</span>
</pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="bash"><span class="line"><span class="c"># Replace yaml header date to current date </span>
</span><span class="line">sed <span class="s2">&quot;s/[0-9]\{4\}.*:[0-9]\{2\}/`date &#39;+%Y-%m-%d %H:%M&#39;`/&quot;</span> <span class="nv">$1</span> &gt; tmp <span class="o">&amp;&amp;</span> mv tmp <span class="nv">$1</span>
</span><span class="line">
</span><span class="line"><span class="nv">mydate</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="k">$(</span>date <span class="s1">&#39;+%Y-%m-%d&#39;</span><span class="k">)</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="nv">fname</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="k">$(</span><span class="nb">echo</span> <span class="nv">$1</span> | sed <span class="s2">&quot;s/text/markdown/&quot;</span><span class="k">)</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="c"># Rename file to current date</span>
</span><span class="line">mv <span class="nv">$1</span> <span class="sb">`</span><span class="nb">echo</span> <span class="nv">$fname</span> | sed <span class="s2">&quot;s/[0-9]\{4\}.*-[0-9]\{2\}-[0-9]\{2\}/$mydate/&quot;</span><span class="sb">`</span>
</span><span class="line">	
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>

<p>It may look like there’s not much automation, but if you think that this runs on my Mac while I’m writing it in my iPod Touch, then it gets really interesting, and the possibilities are almost infinite. Besides, updating the post date, moving files and changing extensions are quite tedious tasks by themselves. To make it automatically generate and deploy the site I’d have to add several more lines to the script, but I’m ok with how it is for now. </p>

<div class="footnotes"><hr>
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:foo2">
      <p>Special thanks to <a href="http://www.neilsmithline.com/">Neil Smithline</a> for helping me out on <a href="https://github.com/imathis/octopress/issues/708">the two blogs one domain issue</a>.<a href="#fnref:foo2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:foo1">
      <p>My Mac or my iPod touch.<a href="#fnref:foo1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:foo5">
      <p>I can’t really write this post without mentioning two posts that served as inspiration and reference: <a href="http://instant-thinking.de/2012/08/03/synced-and-scheduled-blogging-with-octopress/">“Synced and scheduled blogging with octopress”</a> and <a href="http://www.macstories.net/stories/my-dropbox-writing-workflow/" title="My Dropbox Writing Workflow">“My Dropbox Writing Workflow.”</a><a href="#fnref:foo5" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:foo3">
      <p>In some future post I’ll explain my note taking workflow and how I name files. In this case I use <a href="http://www.kungfugrippe.com/post/453204090/q-trick">Merlin Mann’s <code>q</code> trick</a> and the <code>runx</code> stands for running notes.<a href="#fnref:foo3" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:foo4">
      <p>I use several editors, but mainly <a href="http://bywordapp.com/" title="Byword &bull; A Simple Text Editor for Mac and iOS">Byword</a>, <a href="http://writeup.prasannag.com/" title="WriteUp - with Dropbox">WriteUp </a>, <a href="http://www.secondgearsoftware.com/elements/" title="Elements &mdash; Dropbox powered text editor for iPhone, iPad and iPod touch from Second Gear">Elements</a>, and <a href="http://nebulousapps.net/" title="Nebulous Notes">Nebulous Notes</a>.<a href="#fnref:foo4" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spanish keyboard and Aperture]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/07/spanish-keyboard-and-aperture/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-07T00:36:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/07/spanish-keyboard-and-aperture</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="aic" style="width:320px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/8060866808/" title="Mac keyboard by copiancestral, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8030/8060866808_dc3b5dc915_n.jpg" width="320" height="240" alt="20121007-PA077266" /></a><br />
My new keyboard.</div>
<p>It’s been quite a while since I’ve grown accustomed to switching back and forth between an english keyboard at home and a spanish keyboard at work. Like anything, at first it takes a while to get fully accustomed, but all in all it isn’t too bad. This week my English keyboard at home died, so I bought a new one this time in Spanish, because that was what they had at the store. </p>

<p>One of the things I don’t like of the spanish keyboard <sup id="fnref:fn1"><a href="#fn:fn1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> is that most (if not all) applications design the shortcuts assuming an English keyboard. Therefore, what could be single key shortcut in the English keyboard becomes a double key shortcut in the  Spanish keyboard. And that’s not all. </p>

<!--more-->

<p>It just so happens that in some applications, in my case Apple Aperture there are some really nice single key shortcuts like left square bracket (<code>[</code>) for rotating an image counterclockwise, but in the spanish keyboard the bracket, while being in the same place has to be typed with the option (<code>⌥</code>) key. </p>

<p>For some unknown reason Aperture doesn’t recognize this double key shortcut as the single key shortcut I’m trying to reproduce. As a matter of fact it assumes I’m pressing (<code>⌥ `</code>), where the back-tick is the other character sharing the same key as the left square bracket.<sup id="fnref:fn2"><a href="#fn:fn2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup></p>

<div class="aic" style="width:150px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/8060947094/" title="Square bracket by copiancestral, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8034/8060947094_174fee44ff_q.jpg" width="150" height="150" alt="Square bracket" /></a><br />
Square bracket on spanish keyboard.</div>

<p>I have googled a bit about this topic and in an <a href="https://discussions.apple.com/thread/1452719?start=0&amp;tstart=0">apple discussion</a> this was somewhat discussed, but to no great length. And the only solution for the time being is to go to <code>'Aperture' &gt; 'Commands' &gt; 'Customize...'</code>. But I’m still not comfortable changing the default commands in Aperture. I really liked the single key shortcuts for rotating an image and stuff like that. Let’s see how this ends up.</p>

<div class="footnotes"><hr>
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:fn1">
      <p>Or any other keyboard that’s not the English one.<a href="#fnref:fn1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:fn2">
      <p>The reason I hadn’t noticed this is that I don’t use Aperture at work.<a href="#fnref:fn2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[a service for writing day one footnotes inline]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/01/a-service-for-writing-day-one-footnotes-inline/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-01T22:31:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/01/a-service-for-writing-day-one-footnotes-inline</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently wrote about <a href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/09/29/footnotes-in-dayone/">inserting footnotes in Day One</a> and how it could be achieved with the new markdown support. I realize that ideally Day One should support multimarkdown footnotes, but this has not arrived yet. It could well be planned for a future release, but I’ll stick to my solution for the mean time.</p>

<p>One of the tedious things about my solution to footnotes in <a href="http://dayoneapp.com/">Day One</a> is that you have to <em>do</em> everything manually. The insertion of the footnotes <em>plus</em> the formatting, not to mention keeping count of the number of footnotes. For one or two footnotes this doesn’t seem like a big issue. But for several more it gets complicated.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> You have to put the superscript (<code>^</code>), the number of the footnote, the horizontal line (which I think necessary) and the footnote itself. Therefore, I thought I could automate this–somewhat.</p>

<!--more-->

<h2 id="here-comes-the-magic-script">Here comes the magic script</h2>

<p>So I though I’d ask <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/">Brett Terpstra</a><sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> for advice, to see if this could be automated somehow. At the moment he’s probably quite busy with the premiere of his book <a href="http://60tips.com/">60 Mountain Lion Tips</a>, which promises “to turn you into a Mac ninja”. </p>

<p>Despite that, I remembered he had released a service for <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/a-service-for-writing-multimarkdown-footnotes-inline/">writing multimarkdown footnotes inline</a>.  The idea is that you write your text like this</p>

<pre><code>This is the regular text(*This is the footnote*), and you can drop the footnote in at any point.
</code></pre>

<p>You run the service and you get something like this</p>

<pre><code>This is the regular text[^fn1], and you can drop the footnote in at any point.

[^fn1]: This is the footnote
</code></pre>

<p>According to Brett “one nice thing about this syntax is that–if you’re previewing as you write–it italicizes the output to differentiate it until you’ve used the service to move it out of the main text.” So it’s a win-win situation. </p>

<p>I decided I would modify the script, even though I am a <em>neophyte</em> in ruby. The modification is practically nothing, so all the credit goes to Brett. Here’s the modified script</p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/3814178.js"> </script>

<p><strong>Update</strong> on Oct 2, 2012 – Brett took a look at the code and gave it the thumbs up.</p>

<p>I will definitely not go into the details of the script, but I’ve tried it and it works. The only thing I didn’t bother to make work was the part of the code that made sure that footnote reference titles aren’t duplicated if you have existing formatted footnotes in the document. It’s commented out, but feel free to further modify it or make any suggestions. </p>

<p>For the same input as above you should get this</p>

<pre><code>This is the regular text^1, and you can drop the footnote in at any point.

****
1. This is the footnote
</code></pre>

<p>Here’s a <a href="http://d.pr/f/t4ff">download link</a> so you can download it as a system service. You’ll have to move it to <code>~/Library/Services/</code>. Enjoy!</p>

<div class="footnotes"><hr>
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>I don’t usually write long entries in Day One, but hey there’s always a day when I feel <em>so</em> inspired, I could write a short story if I wanted to.<a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>Brett is a computer geek that makes awesome things (most for free) like <a href="http://markedapp.com/">Marked</a> or <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/project/nvalt/">nvAlt</a>. He blogs at <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/">brettterpstra.com</a>, and for what it seems is one of the nicest guys on the internet.<a href="#fnref:2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Footnotes in Day One]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/09/29/footnotes-in-dayone/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T22:51:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/09/29/footnotes-in-dayone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My favorite journaling app, <a href="http://dayoneapp.com/">Day One</a>, just got updated to <a href="http://dayoneapp.com/about/release-notes-mac/">version 1.7.2, and it includes some really great new features</a>.</p>

<p>It now includes more <a href="http://fletcherpenney.net/multimarkdown/">multimarkdown</a> syntax like strike through, fenced code, and other nifty things. However one of the things I still find missing in Day One is multimarkdown footnotes. I’ve grown so accustomed to footnotes, that I don’t think I could live without them anymore.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> </p>

<!--more-->

<p>Footnotes are way better than using parenthesis for digressing a little and adding an additional comment to the sentence. I think that if it’s below four or five words there’s no need for a footnote, but when you pass that threshold the comment is just too long and the footnote is more than welcome. </p>

<p>Until recently I avoided the use of footnotes in Day One because they were not supported, but in this last update they also added superscript (<code>^</code>) support to the markdown syntax. So I thought I could have my temporary solution to the footnote problem by using the superscript and ordered lists. </p>

<p>My custom footnotes are basically the superscript with the number that I have to keep track of manually like</p>

<pre><code>This is a sentence^1
</code></pre>

<p>And the footnote which I add (manually again) at the end of the entry with a horizontal line and ordered lists</p>

<pre><code>****
1. This is a footnote. 
</code></pre>

<p>It looks like this on the Mac</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/8036868919/" title="Day One footnote by copiancestral, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8035/8036868919_3bda9b43d3_z.jpg" width="602" height="241" alt="Day One footnote" /></a></p>

<p>It’s not an optimal solution (in the automation sense), but I’ve found that most of my Day One entries have one or two footnotes, so it’s not really a big deal. I think it’s totally worth the effort. </p>

<div class="footnotes"><hr>
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>I probably could but I would really, <em>really</em> miss them. <a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It makes a difference to know the backstory]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/09/26/the-backstory/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-26T00:29:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/09/26/the-backstory</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="aic" style="width:258px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/8021150733/" title="Selbstporträt by Vincent van Gogh, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8442/8021150733_abdaa02811.jpg" width="258" height="320" alt="Selbstporträt" /></a><br />
selbstporträt by Vincent van Gogh .</div>

<blockquote>
  <p>I think that everybody, to get the screaming out of their heads do different things […] beautiful losers and genius lunatics […] there are people who make things that we really, really admire, and love and feel some kind of a resonance with because the work itself is fantastic, but there’s another level to what they make when you know the backstory […] There are a lot of people whose work I admire that I think partly what brought me to them, in some ways, is knowing that backstory. </p>

  <p>– <strong>Merlin Mann</strong>, <a href="http://5by5.tv/b2w/84">Back to Work Episode #84 - Every Genie is an Actuary.</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>As Feynman spoke once of the science knowledge of a flower,<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> I restate here in another context. There are many interesting questions that come from the knowledge of the backstory of the work of those we admire, which only adds to the excitement and mystery of the work itself. I don’t understand how it subtracts. </p>

<!--more-->

<p>Knowing the backstory makes a great deal of a difference. It sometimes shows you the  human being behind the curtains, and in many ways I truly think that this is good thing. </p>

<p>There are times when I might bring forth a piece of work of by someone I admire. That standalone piece may well be beautiful and quite unique, it may even require no explanation whatsoever, because it is truly a work of art. But then, when you start to grasp on the knowledge behind the work, when you try to unravel the mysteries, it only gets <em>way more</em> interesting. It’s almost like trying to take a peek inside the mind of a grandmaster in the very exact moment he makes a move. I may be exaggerating a little, but it seems so fascinating to be able to get a glimpse on how that amazing idea came to be.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.standard.co.uk/arts/van-gogh-and-his-demons-7418298.html">Whether it be demons</a> or just plain madness, many artists<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> struggle to get the screaming out of their heads, and some even succeed in translating such affliction into beautiful works of art. By trying to empathize with the people you admire, their work transcends to levels you couldn’t have foreseen. Their demons seem much more real to you, and some mysteries start fading away. The world is different, but it sort of makes sense. You feel like you’ve made a connection.</p>

<p>In getting to the backstory you appropriate the work, you make it part of who you are. It no longer is <em>just</em> another thing I read, saw, enjoyed, etc. Traditionally, the backstory to an artist was something not so easily accessible. Quite often I would find myself going through different sources, written posthumously and narrated with the voice of others to get a glance of the seemingly backstory. But things are changing, today I can follow someone in their true voice, in their first person narrated backstory. Today an artist can, and most, willingly convey their story via their personal platform: their web log. </p>

<p>I’ve gone into such length at writing this post because I feel proud of something. I feel proud of following a writer, a great guy by the looks of it, a self publisher,<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> and a contributor to the general conversation and the greater good on the internet. His name is <a href="http://cristianmihai.net/">Christian Mihai</a> and I really don’t remember how I stumbled upon his blog. But now he is on my favorite RSS feeds. This week he’s published a great book called <a href="http://amazon.com/dp/B009FVX9GW">“The Writer”</a> (it’s on sale in amazon). I bought it and so far, so good. Here’s a exceptional quote from the book</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>All great men are misfits, yet I couldn’t help but wonder what was worse: to be like everyone else or to be entirely different. I could only think about the fact that I needed a tragedy in my life, just so I could feel alive, just so my heart wouldn’t stop beating.</p>

  <p>– <strong><a href="http://amazon.com/dp/B009FVX9GW">The Writer, by Cristian Mihai</a></strong></p>
</blockquote>

<!-- - Merlin Mann on btw and mentioning about the backstory. 
- Getting closer to those you admire. 
- Cristian Mihai and "The Writer". 
	- Someone I follow, not necessarily admire. 
	- His book and several quotes. 
 -->

<!-- I think that everybody to get the screaming out of their heads do different things […] Half a dozen people beautiful losers and genius lunatics  There are these people who have created these things where part of what makes us admire them, there are people who make things that we really, really admire, and love and feel some kind of a resonance with because the work itself is fantastic, but there's another level to what they make when you know the backstory 
Brian Wislon
Vincent Van Gogh
Alex Chilton
Chad Baker
There are a lot of people whose work I admire that I think partly what brought me to them in some ways is knowing that backstory  -->
<div class="footnotes"><hr>
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p><a href="http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Richard_Feynman">Feynman originally said</a>, “There are all kinds of interesting questions that come from a knowledge of science, which only adds to the excitement and mystery and awe of a flower. It only adds. I don’t understand how it subtracts.”<a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>When I write “artist” I mean anyone that <em>makes</em> something he can be proud of. <a href="#fnref:2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3">
      <p>Which to me means a great thing.<a href="#fnref:3" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm writing the site I want to read]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/09/19/the-site-i-want-to-read/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-19T23:32:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/09/19/the-site-i-want-to-read</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="aic" style="width:240px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/8004479709/" title="a day in the life of striatic ~ end of day accident by striatic, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8313/8004479709_2bfe1eb43a_n.jpg" width="240" height="320" alt="a day in the life of striatic ~ end of day accident" /></a><br />
photo by striatic.</div>

<p>If there’s something I learned from the famous talk “<a href="http://www.43folders.com/2009/03/25/blogs-turbocharged">149 Surprising Ways to Turbocharge Your Blog With Credibility!</a>” by <a href="http://daringfireball.net/">John Gruber</a> and <a href="http://www.merlinmann.com/">Merlin Mann</a>,  was that one should make a great effort to write as if the people you admire we’re going to read your work. This is true even if the people you admire are fictional, or like in Gruber’s case, an idealized version of himself. 
I like to think that this piece of advice is as valid for writing/blogging as it is for anything else you do in life.
<!--more--> </p>

<p>I can certainly say that I personally don’t know most of the people I admire,<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> which is fine by me. But I don’t write exclusively for them. Quite often, if not always, I write for myself.<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> I write as a way to remind my future self of what it felt to be me in the past.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> I write to the better version of myself, in the hopes that by doing so, my worse version recognizes his mistakes and learns from them. </p>

<p>In some ways my ideal reader <em>is</em> the better version of myself. More often than not I find myself reading my own articles several times after they’ve been published. It certainly is not a narcissistic thing,<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">4</a></sup> I just really like to feel proud of what I make. This is why <em>I write the site I want to read</em>. </p>

<div class="footnotes"><hr>
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>This, without much doubt will continue to stay this way, for some of them are dead, and believing in the afterlife is plain foolishness. <a href="#fnref:2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:4">
      <p>I had been meaning to write this post for quite a while, but hadn’t found time to do so. However, Gabe Weatherhead’s post on his <a href="http://macdrifter.com/2012/09/audience-and-my-multiple-personalities.html">Audience and Multiple Personalities</a> prompted me to write it in a flash. Thanks Gabe. <a href="#fnref:4" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Trust me, one easily forgets how things felt in the very moment you were experiencing them. And all that is left is a vague reminder of what happened. <a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3">
      <p>Or so I like to think. <a href="#fnref:3" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
