<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: life | andres marrugo]]></title>
  <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2020-12-28T02:22:25-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andres Marrugo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nothing Besides Remains]]></title>
    <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2020/03/02/nothing-besides-remains/"/>
    <updated>2020-03-02T23:12:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2020/03/02/nothing-besides-remains</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I was scrolling through twitter, I happened to come across this beautiful thread that spoke of the lessons learned by a researcher while contemplating his research in the grand scheme of things. Though he was passionate about his research and the questions he was trying to answer, there would come a time when future researchers - with the advantage of hindsight - would contemplate his work as obsolete and irrelevant. But the truth is that we all have to come to terms with this situation. </p>

<p>It starts with this tweet:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">1. One of formative experience of grad school for me was when our lab moved across the hallway to a bigger space &amp; I realised my research didn’t really matter in the grand scheme of science &amp; that this actually made me love science even more. So here is a thread about that.</p>&mdash; Tanentzapf Lab (@TanentzapfLab) <a href="https://twitter.com/TanentzapfLab/status/1232732701687287808?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 26, 2020</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>He came to this realization when he had the opportunity to sit down and listen to someone older than him who had gone through the same excitement for science as he was at that moment. He was young and arrogant. To him, the work of those old guys seemed quaint and had long been solved by other means. But the message that got to him was when that person told him, “we thought what we were doing was the best science.” Also, they had trained many successful scientists in their lab. </p>

<p>So it all boils down to the mere revelation that we should be humble, but still strive to do our best. While in the future, our work may be irrelevant, it is only in hindsight that this judgment should be made, but even if it does become irrelevant for the future, in the present, it is still worthwhile doing. Just the mere fact of training future researchers is an enterprise worth investing in. Because they become the ones that invent the <em>new</em> and more <em>exciting</em> ways of conducting research. </p>

<p>To this thread, someone replied with a quote from the famous poem Ozymandias by Percy Shelley.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Ozymandias</p>

  <p>I met a traveller from an antique land
Who said: Two vast and trunkless legs of stone
Stand in the desert. Near them, on the sand,
Half sunk, a shattered visage lies, whose frown,
And wrinkled lip, and sneer of cold command,
Tell that its sculptor well those passions read
Which yet survive, stamped on these lifeless things,
The hand that mocked them and the heart that fed.
And on the pedestal these words appear:
“My name is Ozymandias, king of kings:
Look on my works, ye Mighty, and despair!”
Nothing beside remains. Round the decay
Of that colossal wreck, boundless and bare
The lone and level sands stretch far away</p>
</blockquote>

<p>He might have been mighty in his day. But all that remains from his empire is sand. So, let’s look at things in context. We know nothing will last forever. Let’s enjoy it while it lasts. If you are passionate about your craft. Keep doing it because you love it, not because you think someone in the future is going to find it useful. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life immutable]]></title>
    <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2015/10/10/life-inmutable/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-10T22:34:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2015/10/10/life-inmutable</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a data-flickr-embed="true" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/22093344571/in/datetaken/" title="Life immutable."><img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/724/22093344571_5a128fb7da.jpg" width="500" height="379" alt="Life immutable." /></a><script async="" src="http://agmarrugo.github.com//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>

<p>We often live worrying about the future and longing for a less troublesome past; like when we were kids. I know that not everyone had a <em>perfect</em> childhood. I certainly did not, but I still had my moments in which my joy was true and worry free. Those moments are precious to me. </p>

<p>Adulthood has many upsides when viewed from a teenager’s perspective; the opposite is also true. If only they could talk to each other. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Praise of Slow]]></title>
    <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2015/08/07/in-praise-of-slow/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-07T23:53:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2015/08/07/in-praise-of-slow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have a recurrent discussion with my wife. </p>

<p>She likes to do most things as <em>fast</em> as possible. </p>

<p>I like to pause and think about things, and do them often <em>slowly</em>. At my pace. </p>

<p>I think that if you do things too quickly you might not be fully aware of what you’re doing. </p>

<p>You might feel that you are not really in charge of your life. </p>

<p>You might feel that you can’t  really remember things truly. </p>

<p>Like nothing becomes a memorable experience. </p>

<p>You have no time for metacognition and self-awareness. </p>

<p>I wrote these lines before finding out about this book <a href="http://www.carlhonore.com/books/in-praise-of-slowness/" title="In Praise of Slow | Carl Honoré">In Praise of Slow by Carl Honoré.</a> It seems this has inspired the slow-movement which tries to raise awareness of how we need to take it easy and enjoy life. Like the saying goes, <a href="http://mobile.brainyquote.com/quotes/quotes/m/maewest163658.html" title="Anything worth doing is worth doing slowly. - Mae West at BrainyQuote Mobile">anything worth doing is worth doing slowly.</a></p>

<p>It seems I have a new book to read. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On (re)learning things]]></title>
    <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2015/01/29/on-relearning-things/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-29T22:47:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2015/01/29/on-relearning-things</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>My favorite topic in an introductory differential equations course is mechanical and electrical vibrations. I enjoyed learning about it as a student and I enjoyed teaching it later. (Or more accurately, I enjoyed being exposed to it as a student and really learning it later when I had to teach it.)</p>

  <p>John D. Cook on <a href="http://www.johndcook.com/blog/2013/02/19/mechanical-vibrations/">Mechanical vibrations</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>I’ve always thought that education is about learning, as much as parenting is about maturing and growing up. On the parenting side, you can’t really teach your kids how to live – <a href="http://www.radiolab.org/story/288746-future-cant-control/" title="A Future You Can't Control - Radiolab">you can’t even imagine the kind of world they will have to live from the time they’re born</a> – but you <em>can</em> expose them to the best things you know. In doing so, they can at least have the chance to form an opinion on the many matters of life, they’ll surely make mistakes, but I bet they won’t regret much. </p>

<p>Education is a difficult topic. Everyone has something to say about it, yet no one seems to have true answers. I do think that education is much more about being exposed to something, rather than being taught that something. There’s an incredible difference between the two things.  </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not Collapsing the Wave Function]]></title>
    <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2014/01/31/not-collapsing-the-wave-function/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-31T09:32:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2014/01/31/not-collapsing-the-wave-function</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today in <a href="http://www.thisamericanlife.org/radio-archives/episode/399/contents-unknown" title="Contents Unknown | This American Life">“This American Life”</a> I was listening to an episode about hidden truths. It was really interesting to find out about a secret letter that the prime minister of Britain writes to every commander of a nuclear submarine. It supposedly contains instructions on what to do if the nation has been wiped out and if the commander should retaliate or not. It poses a mystery on what the contents are, even more so because every time there’s a new prime minister in office the letters are destroyed unread.</p>

<p>There are many questions that come about in knowing what the contents of the letter are. But to my understanding it is a way of reassuring your people that both possibilities exist. To retaliate or not. It is like delaying the final call on a difficult decision. Something akin to a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schrodinger_cat" title="Schrödinger's cat - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia">Schrödinger cat situation</a>.  </p>

<p>I’ve thought of this for while and I’ve come to understand that many people actually <em>like</em> to live their lives this way. Not wanting to know certain things, or more precisely clinging to the hope that a certain aspect in one’s life does not turn out to be what we fear so much. Keeping both options open (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wave_function" title="Wave function - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia"><em>not collapsing the wave function</em></a>) is probably a reassuring situation, relieving anxiety and allowing one to continue living unmoved by the cold hard reality. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
