<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: book | andres marrugo]]></title>
  <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/categories/book/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-12-06T09:54:48-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andres Marrugo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It makes a difference to know the backstory]]></title>
    <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2012/09/26/the-backstory/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-26T00:29:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2012/09/26/the-backstory</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="aic" style="width:258px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/8021150733/" title="Selbstporträt by Vincent van Gogh, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8442/8021150733_abdaa02811.jpg" width="258" height="320" alt="Selbstporträt" /></a><br />
selbstporträt by Vincent van Gogh .</div>

<blockquote>
  <p>I think that everybody, to get the screaming out of their heads do different things […] beautiful losers and genius lunatics […] there are people who make things that we really, really admire, and love and feel some kind of a resonance with because the work itself is fantastic, but there’s another level to what they make when you know the backstory […] There are a lot of people whose work I admire that I think partly what brought me to them, in some ways, is knowing that backstory. </p>

  <p>– <strong>Merlin Mann</strong>, <a href="http://5by5.tv/b2w/84">Back to Work Episode #84 - Every Genie is an Actuary.</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>As Feynman spoke once of the science knowledge of a flower,<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> I restate here in another context. There are many interesting questions that come from the knowledge of the backstory of the work of those we admire, which only adds to the excitement and mystery of the work itself. I don’t understand how it subtracts. </p>

<!--more-->

<p>Knowing the backstory makes a great deal of a difference. It sometimes shows you the  human being behind the curtains, and in many ways I truly think that this is good thing. </p>

<p>There are times when I might bring forth a piece of work of by someone I admire. That standalone piece may well be beautiful and quite unique, it may even require no explanation whatsoever, because it is truly a work of art. But then, when you start to grasp on the knowledge behind the work, when you try to unravel the mysteries, it only gets <em>way more</em> interesting. It’s almost like trying to take a peek inside the mind of a grandmaster in the very exact moment he makes a move. I may be exaggerating a little, but it seems so fascinating to be able to get a glimpse on how that amazing idea came to be.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.standard.co.uk/arts/van-gogh-and-his-demons-7418298.html">Whether it be demons</a> or just plain madness, many artists<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> struggle to get the screaming out of their heads, and some even succeed in translating such affliction into beautiful works of art. By trying to empathize with the people you admire, their work transcends to levels you couldn’t have foreseen. Their demons seem much more real to you, and some mysteries start fading away. The world is different, but it sort of makes sense. You feel like you’ve made a connection.</p>

<p>In getting to the backstory you appropriate the work, you make it part of who you are. It no longer is <em>just</em> another thing I read, saw, enjoyed, etc. Traditionally, the backstory to an artist was something not so easily accessible. Quite often I would find myself going through different sources, written posthumously and narrated with the voice of others to get a glance of the seemingly backstory. But things are changing, today I can follow someone in their true voice, in their first person narrated backstory. Today an artist can, and most, willingly convey their story via their personal platform: their web log. </p>

<p>I’ve gone into such length at writing this post because I feel proud of something. I feel proud of following a writer, a great guy by the looks of it, a self publisher,<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> and a contributor to the general conversation and the greater good on the internet. His name is <a href="http://cristianmihai.net/">Christian Mihai</a> and I really don’t remember how I stumbled upon his blog. But now he is on my favorite RSS feeds. This week he’s published a great book called <a href="http://amazon.com/dp/B009FVX9GW">“The Writer”</a> (it’s on sale in amazon). I bought it and so far, so good. Here’s a exceptional quote from the book</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>All great men are misfits, yet I couldn’t help but wonder what was worse: to be like everyone else or to be entirely different. I could only think about the fact that I needed a tragedy in my life, just so I could feel alive, just so my heart wouldn’t stop beating.</p>

  <p>– <strong><a href="http://amazon.com/dp/B009FVX9GW">The Writer, by Cristian Mihai</a></strong></p>
</blockquote>

<!-- - Merlin Mann on btw and mentioning about the backstory. 
- Getting closer to those you admire. 
- Cristian Mihai and "The Writer". 
	- Someone I follow, not necessarily admire. 
	- His book and several quotes. 
 -->

<!-- I think that everybody to get the screaming out of their heads do different things […] Half a dozen people beautiful losers and genius lunatics  There are these people who have created these things where part of what makes us admire them, there are people who make things that we really, really admire, and love and feel some kind of a resonance with because the work itself is fantastic, but there's another level to what they make when you know the backstory 
Brian Wislon
Vincent Van Gogh
Alex Chilton
Chad Baker
There are a lot of people whose work I admire that I think partly what brought me to them in some ways is knowing that backstory  -->
<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p><a href="http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Richard_Feynman">Feynman originally said</a>, “There are all kinds of interesting questions that come from a knowledge of science, which only adds to the excitement and mystery and awe of a flower. It only adds. I don’t understand how it subtracts.”<a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>When I write “artist” I mean anyone that <em>makes</em> something he can be proud of. <a href="#fnref:2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3">
      <p>Which to me means a great thing.<a href="#fnref:3" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the human intellect and prehistoric people]]></title>
    <link href="http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2012/09/11/on-the-human-intellect-and-prehistoric-people/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-11T17:53:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agmarrugo.github.com/blog/2012/09/11/on-the-human-intellect-and-prehistoric-people</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="aic" style="width:500px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/7977735786/" title="Lascaux by JackVersloot, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8441/7977735786_aecd77b178.jpg" width="500" height="333" alt="Lascaux" /></a><br />
photo by JackVersloot.</div>

<p>I recently finished reading <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Clan_of_the_Cave_Bear">“The Clan of the Cave Bear”</a> by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jean_M._Auel">Jean M. Auel</a>. It is a beautiful story of the human struggle for survival. In the time of mammoths and cave lions, a young human girl finds herself orphan because of an earthquake. Her survival instincts are put to test at their maximum, but she knows very little of surviving on her own. This desolate picture changes when she is rescued by a group of Neanderthals, the “clan of the cave bear”. She looks like them a bit, but at the same time she is too different to be accepted without it raising a few concerns. </p>

<!--more-->

<p>I liked this story, not for it’s detailed description of a world that is as strange to us, as our world surely is to the prehistoric people, but mainly because of the triumph of the human intellect above anything else. I was deeply moved by the rationalization of Ayla, the main character, and how she struggles to overcome her fears and adapting herself to the customs of the clan. I recommend this book be read with a keen eye on these intellectual moments, they are both emotional and entertaining. </p>

<p>When reading this book I realized that the triumph of the human intellect is what really makes me fall for a story. The very same feature that makes us human is what makes us succeed. In every single story that I’ve found amusing, if not by wits or careful planned strategy or even divine inspiration in the form of genius, the plot is moved on and finally solved by the use of our intellect. Anything departing from this direction I find absolutely boring<sup id="fnref:foo"><a href="#fn:foo" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>. Our intellect is what makes us stronger, faster, resilient, and ultimately truly human.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:foo">
      <p>I can’t stand an author that describes absolutely everything, from the ceiling fan to the toilet, and above else uses five different adjectives that technically mean the same thing. I care about the human character, not so much about the decor. <a href="#fnref:foo" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
