<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: blogging | andres marrugo]]></title>
  <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/categories/blogging/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-30T01:21:56-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andres Marrugo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Always Late to The Party]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/22/always-late-to-the-party/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-22T00:11:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/22/always-late-to-the-party</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="to-tweet-or-not-to-tweet">To Tweet or Not to Tweet</h2>

<p>It always seems I’m late to the party. For several years I pondered on the idea of joining <a href="https://twitter.com/" title="Twitter">Twitter</a>, but it never really made much sense to me – at least at the time – to join a social network where there were hardly any friends of mine<sup id="fnref:fn1"><a href="#fn:fn1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>. Big mistake, that actually <em>is</em> one of the cool things about twitter. Unlike Facebook, it <em>does</em> provides an open space suitable for engaging in discussions, albeit short, of all sorts with interesting people who don’t really have to be your “friend.”</p>

<p>It turns out that shortly after joining twitter most people<sup id="fnref:fn2"><a href="#fn:fn2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> were already considering abandoning it in favor of <a href="https://join.app.net/" title="Join the Movement - App.net">App.net</a>. For the time being <a href="https://join.app.net/" title="Join the Movement - App.net">App.net</a> seems like a <em>niche</em> thing, and most people seem to continue on twitter. Whether that stays that way for the next year or so depends on twitter and their recent policy changes that could well endanger the platform as we know it today. </p>

<!--more-->

<h2 id="its-all-about-the-editor">It’s All About The Editor</h2>

<p>For quite a while it seemed that everywhere I looked, geeks where rejoicing and feeling proud of their text editor of choice: <a href="http://macromates.com/" title="TextMate — The Missing Editor for Mac OS X">Textmate</a>. I did look into it a couple of times, but I always thought it ways a bit too expensive for me. </p>

<p>For the most part it seemed I had always managed to get by with the tools at my disposal, I really didn’t feel like I needed something else.
I would use the builtin Matlab editor for writing Matlab code. As regards LaTeX – for writing papers – I would use the open source and free (as in beer) <a href="http://www.xm1math.net/texmaker/" title="Texmaker (free cross-platform latex editor)">Texmaker</a>. I really wasn’t aware of the exciting and cool features of <em>advanced</em> text editors like Textmate or <a href="http://www.vim.org/" title="welcome home : vim online">Vim</a>. </p>

<p>For as long as I can remember, I’ve been a computer enthusiast, but a lone one. I never did have close friends that were into the sort of things I liked. I was never really ostracized, but I <em>was</em> the “nerd” nevertheless. </p>

<p>This brief digression is not without a purpose, which is to bring forth the fact that despite being a geek, I’ve never been part of a geek community of any sort. And this influenced my way of life and how I – before social networks – ended up finding out about the latest and coolest thing. More often than not, late and when it wasn’t really a <em>new</em> thing. The text editor dilemma is proof to my lack of geeky-social interaction.</p>

<p>Before I bought Textmate, I <em>did</em> do a little background check to see what was happening to its development. Apparently it was being not-so-actively developed, but version 2.0 was on the way. I had managed to somehow convince myself that it was totally worth it and that I would write my thesis with it. </p>

<p>Shortly after I bought it, it went open source, and to the impression of some: abandoned. It seems that for quite some time, everyone had been moving to Sublime text or BBEdit. Late to the party once again. I just can’t stop thinking that if somehow I had looked into it a bit more, if I had participated more on forums and different communities all of this would have ended differently. I <em>can</em> however say, that I am still using Textmate 1,  and I’m enjoying my self quite a bit.</p>

<h2 id="a-static-or-dynamic-blog">A Static or Dynamic Blog</h2>

<p>Technically speaking I’ve been bloggin since 2010. However, I must be honest and admit that for about the first year of my <a href="http://copiancestral.wordpress.com/" title="Between the Candle and the Star | Academia, Computing, and other topics.">(former) blog</a> I hardly posted a thing or two. It was a <a href="http://wordpress.com/" title="WordPress.com — Get a Free Blog Here">wordpress.com</a> blog and for nearly the last year or so, I began posting more regularly and I was really enjoying myself. I rapidly got accustomed to wordpress; so much, that I felt trapped in the platform, and I needed more customization to set things my way. Well, for the looks of it, I had to leave wordpress.com and move my blog somewhere else in order to do just that.</p>

<p>I kept blogging there, while I looked around to explore my options. It was interesting that this time I was <em>also</em> late, but not so much in the sense that I was able to catch a lot of people during their <a href="http://www.macdrifter.com/migrating-to-pelican-extracting-wordpress-data.html" title="Migrating to Pelican - Extracting WordPress Data">migration from a dynamic blog to a static one</a>. I’m not going to go through the details of why I chose a static blog, but it does have its advantages with respect to a dynamic one, like wordpress. </p>

<h2 id="getting-stuff-done">Getting Stuff Done</h2>

<p>As a final section for this already long post, I’d like to mention how I’ve also been late to the whole GTD movement (if there is such a thing). It’s amusing how shortly after I started to actually read David Allen’s book on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Getting_Things_Done" title="Getting Things Done - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia">“Getting Things Done”</a>, some people were already arguing </p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“whether GTD [was] valid after more than 10 years without any real “update”.”</p>

  <p>– <strong>Sven Fechner</strong>, <a href="http://simplicitybliss.com/the-state-of-getting-things-done" title="The State of Getting Things Done — SimplicityBliss">The State of Getting Things Done.</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>I can’t really say for my self, if it is still valid. I can, however, say that it still seems to make sense in the philosophy behind it, probably not so much in the methodology. But hey, what can I say, I haven’t even finished the <em>goddamn</em> book.</p>

<p>I’ve been late, as always, to many fascinating events of recent years – at least the geeky ones it seems. But I’ve come to accept that as a reality of mine. These days I can say that I try to keep myself more in the loop by following several interesting people on the web, whether it be via their blogs, twitter, or podcasts. This  seems a bit of a remedy to my bad timing, but hey everyone’s entitled to do things their way. I’m still struggling to actually find what <em>is</em> “my way”, but I’m in no hurry. There probably isn’t any <em>real</em> answer, <a href="http://www.macdrifter.com/2012/08/fiddle-sticks.html" title="Fiddle Sticks">I reckon the search is more valuable than the goal itself.</a></p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:fn1">
      <p>I <em>still</em> have few close friends on twitter; most of them are rarely active. As regards Facebook, I cannot say the same. <a href="#fnref:fn1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:fn2">
      <p>When I say <em>most</em> people, I actually mean the majority of people worth following. <a href="#fnref:fn2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My blog post writing workflow with Dropbox and Hazel]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/15/blog-post-writing-workflow-dropbox-hazel/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-15T23:44:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/10/15/blog-post-writing-workflow-dropbox-hazel</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It may seem that, for the most part, I’ve been blogging about blogging. No matter how pointless it seems, I <em>do</em> think that this could prove useful to someone, in the same way I have benefited from others while setting up this site<sup id="fnref:foo2"><a href="#fn:foo2" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>.</p>

<p>One of the things I like about having an <a href="http://octopress.org/" title="Octopress">Octopress</a> driven <code>txt</code>-only blog is that I have the liberty to set things my way. The topic I am addressing here is that of writing blog posts on different devices<sup id="fnref:foo1"><a href="#fn:foo1" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> with the help of Dropbox<sup id="fnref:foo5"><a href="#fn:foo5" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> and <a href="http://www.noodlesoft.com/hazel.php" title="Noodlesoft | Hazel">Hazel</a>. I’m still working out the whole remote blogging thing, this is but the first stage of a soon-to-be remote blogging workflow with Octopress. </p>

<!--more-->

<!-- When I say "different devices" I actually mean three:

- A Macbook Pro at the office, almost always on.
- A Mac Mini at home, often on, but not necessary logged in my user.
- An iPod Touch, always with me. -->

<h2 id="my-blog-post-writing-workflow">My blog post writing workflow</h2>

<p>Ideally any blog post starts with an idea that I write down in a text file named <code>runx-blog_ideas-qqq.txt</code><sup id="fnref:foo3"><a href="#fn:foo3" rel="footnote">4</a></sup>. This is done either on any of the two Macs using <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/project/nvalt/" title="nvALT 2.1 - Notational Velocity Fork">nvAlt</a> or on my iOS device using any text editor<sup id="fnref:foo4"><a href="#fn:foo4" rel="footnote">5</a></sup>. I <em>always</em> write in <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/" title="Daring Fireball: Markdown">Markdown</a> (technically I <em>mostly</em> write in <a href="http://fletcherpenney.net/multimarkdown/" title="MultiMarkdown">Multimarkdown</a>, but that’s another thing). </p>

<p>After I decide that this idea is ready to become a draft, I create a text file that follows the same name convention for Octopress (<code>2012-10-14-Post-title.text</code>) on a folder named <code>_drafts</code> that resides in the <code>source</code>. You might have noticed that the extension is not <code>.markdown</code> and that is because I was having issues <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/fixing-spotlight-indexing-of-markdown-content/" title="Fixing Spotlight indexing of Markdown content - Brett Terpstra">making Hazel read the contents of markdown files</a>. So I opted for <code>.text</code> which is technically the same as <code>.txt</code>, but I would differentiate them as drafts and most <em>importantly</em> <a href="http://macsparky.com/2009/6/3/sorting-and-moving-documents-with-hazel.html" title="Sorting and Moving Documents with Hazel — MacSparky">Hazel will be able to do its magic</a>.</p>

<p>The underscore (<code>_</code>) on the name of the drafts folder is so that it won’t be deployed, just as the posts folder</p>

<pre><code>source/
|__ _drafts/
|__ _posts/
</code></pre>

<p>With the help of <a href="http://www.ergonis.com/products/typinator/" title="Typinator - the fastest text expander in town">Typinator</a> on my mac or <a href="http://smilesoftware.com/TextExpander/touch/index.html" title="TextExpander touch: iOS Typing Shortcuts for iPhone and iPad">Textexpander</a> on my iPod I create the yaml header like this</p>

<pre><code>--- 
layout: post 
title: "Post title" 
date: 2012-10-14 23:28 
author: Andres Marrugo 
comments: true 
published: false 
categories: [blog] 
--- 
</code></pre>

<p>Notice that <code>published: false</code>, which means <em>it is a draft</em>. When I’m finished with the post I’ll change it to <code>true</code>. </p>

<h3 id="the-syncing">The Syncing</h3>

<p>The Syncing is done via Dropbox, because any iOS text editor comes with Dropbox support. iCloud has still a long way to go. Because my octopress folder does not reside in the Dropbox folder I made symlinks on my Mac to the <code>_posts</code>, <code>_drafts</code>, and <code>images</code> folders so they get synced </p>

<pre><code>ln -s ~/octopress/source/_posts/ ~/Dropbox/PlainText/blog/_posts
ln -s ~/octopress/source/images/ ~/Dropbox/PlainText/blog/images
ln -s ~/octopress/source/_drafts/ ~/Dropbox/PlainText/blog/_drafts
</code></pre>

<p>On any other machine they become actual folders.</p>

<h3 id="automating-with-hazel">Automating with Hazel</h3>

<p>Ideally I would like to change the <code>published: false</code> to <code>true</code> and have it posted to my site, but it still requires some workarounds and this is why for the time being my hazel magic script only moves the file to the <code>_posts</code> folder when the published option changes to <code>true</code>. I then generate the site and deploy it manually, but this will soon be automated as well.</p>

<p>There are actually two Hazel rules for this. It first monitors the <code>_drafts</code> folder for files whose content contains the phrase <code>published: true</code>. When this happens the file gets moved to the folder <code>_posts</code>.</p>

<div class="aic" style="width:500px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/7913589162/" title="drafts-move-to-posts-hazel by copiancestral, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8038/7913589162_551eed930a.jpg" width="500" height="243" alt="drafts-move-to-posts-hazel" /></a><br />
Move file to _posts folder.</div>

<p>Then the second rule is for the <code>_posts</code> folder. If the extension is <code>text</code> (which means it was a draft that recently got moved) it will run a shell script.</p>

<div class="aic" style="width:500px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/7913591478/" title="posts-modify-latest-post-hazel by copiancestral, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8458/7913591478_f75d933161.jpg" width="500" height="356" alt="posts-modify-latest-post-hazel" /></a><br />
Modify latest post.</div>

<p>The shell script is the following. What it does is to replace the date with the current date – you see, several days could’ve passed since I created the draft – in both the yaml header and the file name. And the other thing it does is to change the extension to <code>.markdown</code>.  </p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><figcaption><span>Move to posts folder   </span></figcaption>
 <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>&lt;/p&gt;
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;h1 <span class="nv">id</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&quot;replace-yaml-header-date-to-current-date&quot;</span>&gt;Replace yaml header date to current date&lt;/h1&gt;
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p&gt;sed “s/<span class="o">[</span>0-9<span class="o">]{</span>4<span class="o">}</span>.*:<span class="o">[</span>0-9<span class="o">]{</span>2<span class="o">}</span>/&lt;code&gt;date <span class="s1">&#39;+%Y-%m-%d %H:%M&#39;</span>&lt;/code&gt;/” <span class="nv">$1</span> &amp;gt; tmp &amp;amp;&amp;amp; mv tmp <span class="nv">$1</span>&lt;/p&gt;
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p&gt;mydate<span class="o">=</span><span class="k">$(</span>date ‘+%Y-%m-%d’<span class="k">)</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">fname</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="k">$(</span><span class="nb">echo</span> <span class="nv">$1</span> | sed “s/text/markdown/”<span class="k">)</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c"># Rename file to current date</span>
</span><span class='line'>mv <span class="nv">$1</span> &lt;code&gt;echo <span class="nv">$fname</span> | sed <span class="s2">&quot;s/[0-9]\{4\}.*-[0-9]\{2\}-[0-9]\{2\}/$mydate/&quot;</span>&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p&gt;
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>It may look like there’s not much automation, but if you think that this runs on my Mac while I’m writing it in my iPod Touch, then it gets really interesting, and the possibilities are almost infinite. Besides, updating the post date, moving files and changing extensions are quite tedious tasks by themselves. To make it automatically generate and deploy the site I’d have to add several more lines to the script, but I’m ok with how it is for now. </p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:foo2">
      <p>Special thanks to <a href="http://www.neilsmithline.com/">Neil Smithline</a> for helping me out on <a href="https://github.com/imathis/octopress/issues/708">the two blogs one domain issue</a>.<a href="#fnref:foo2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:foo1">
      <p>My Mac or my iPod touch.<a href="#fnref:foo1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:foo5">
      <p>I can’t really write this post without mentioning two posts that served as inspiration and reference: <a href="http://instant-thinking.de/2012/08/03/synced-and-scheduled-blogging-with-octopress/">“Synced and scheduled blogging with octopress”</a> and <a href="http://www.macstories.net/stories/my-dropbox-writing-workflow/" title="My Dropbox Writing Workflow">“My Dropbox Writing Workflow.”</a><a href="#fnref:foo5" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:foo3">
      <p>In some future post I’ll explain my note taking workflow and how I name files. In this case I use <a href="http://www.kungfugrippe.com/post/453204090/q-trick">Merlin Mann’s <code>q</code> trick</a> and the <code>runx</code> stands for running notes.<a href="#fnref:foo3" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:foo4">
      <p>I use several editors, but mainly <a href="http://bywordapp.com/" title="Byword &bull; A Simple Text Editor for Mac and iOS">Byword</a>, <a href="http://writeup.prasannag.com/" title="WriteUp - with Dropbox">WriteUp </a>, <a href="http://www.secondgearsoftware.com/elements/" title="Elements &mdash; Dropbox powered text editor for iPhone, iPad and iPod touch from Second Gear">Elements</a>, and <a href="http://nebulousapps.net/" title="Nebulous Notes">Nebulous Notes</a>.<a href="#fnref:foo4" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm writing the site I want to read]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/09/19/the-site-i-want-to-read/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-19T23:32:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/09/19/the-site-i-want-to-read</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="aic" style="width:240px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/8004479709/" title="a day in the life of striatic ~ end of day accident by striatic, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8313/8004479709_2bfe1eb43a_n.jpg" width="240" height="320" alt="a day in the life of striatic ~ end of day accident" /></a><br />
photo by striatic.</div>

<p>If there’s something I learned from the famous talk “<a href="http://www.43folders.com/2009/03/25/blogs-turbocharged">149 Surprising Ways to Turbocharge Your Blog With Credibility!</a>” by <a href="http://daringfireball.net/">John Gruber</a> and <a href="http://www.merlinmann.com/">Merlin Mann</a>,  was that one should make a great effort to write as if the people you admire we’re going to read your work. This is true even if the people you admire are fictional, or like in Gruber’s case, an idealized version of himself. 
I like to think that this piece of advice is as valid for writing/blogging as it is for anything else you do in life.
<!--more--> </p>

<p>I can certainly say that I personally don’t know most of the people I admire,<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> which is fine by me. But I don’t write exclusively for them. Quite often, if not always, I write for myself.<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> I write as a way to remind my future self of what it felt to be me in the past.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> I write to the better version of myself, in the hopes that by doing so, my worse version recognizes his mistakes and learns from them. </p>

<p>In some ways my ideal reader <em>is</em> the better version of myself. More often than not I find myself reading my own articles several times after they’ve been published. It certainly is not a narcissistic thing,<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">4</a></sup> I just really like to feel proud of what I make. This is why <em>I write the site I want to read</em>. </p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>This, without much doubt will continue to stay this way, for some of them are dead, and believing in the afterlife is plain foolishness. <a href="#fnref:2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:4">
      <p>I had been meaning to write this post for quite a while, but hadn’t found time to do so. However, Gabe Weatherhead’s post on his <a href="http://macdrifter.com/2012/09/audience-and-my-multiple-personalities.html">Audience and Multiple Personalities</a> prompted me to write it in a flash. Thanks Gabe. <a href="#fnref:4" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Trust me, one easily forgets how things felt in the very moment you were experiencing them. And all that is left is a vague reminder of what happened. <a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3">
      <p>Or so I like to think. <a href="#fnref:3" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I care about blogging]]></title>
    <link href="http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/08/27/why-i-care-about-blogging/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-27T15:47:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andresmarrugo.net/blog/2012/08/27/why-i-care-about-blogging</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="ail" style="width:247px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/copiancestral/7890587640/" title="Blogging Fun! by Mike Licht, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8313/7890587640_f1ddb21e38_n.jpg" width="247" height="320" alt="Blogging Fun!" /></a><br />
photo by Mike Licht. </div>

<p>It’s been about two and a half years since I started blogging. It was on a blog called <a href="copiancestral.wordpress.com">Between the Candle and the Star (BTCATS)</a> which I still keep, but feel I’ll be leaving aside indefinitely<sup id="fnref:foo"><a href="#fn:foo" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>, and continue my writing on this site. </p>

<p>My original intention with BTCATS was to have a place were to write about something I had managed to solve or fix so it could be helpful to others. The blog has moderately met this goal. However, on the first year or so, I barely published a handful of posts.  About a year ago, shortly after my son was born, things started to get interesting. <!--more-->  When you have a newborn, the first few months are quite difficult and stressing. You hardly get any sleep, you have to be there 24/7 and you have to have a lot of patience. Oddly enough, without having the spare time I had before, blogging came to me in the moment of greatest need. And to be honest, it has helped me a lot ever since. </p>

<p>One of the things I noticed was that I started (or wanted) to blog more frequently and with more elaborated content. More often than not, I would find my self blogging about topics somewhat unrelated to the tech and nerdy stuff I usually wrote about. Without really knowing it, I had slowly been converting my blog from a <a href="http://52tiger.net/the-blogging-cycle-back-to-the-beginning/" title="THE BLOGGING CYCLE – BACK TO THE BEGINNING">niche blog to a personality blog</a>. One that represented my character and my voice, not only a hobby of mine. In some ways, this site  is a tribute to that change.   </p>

<p>I must be honest and admit that the changes did not start to happen all of a sudden. It was an interesting time for me. I had recently become a father and that alone pushed me to see things from a totally different perspective. I started to care more about things like <a href="http://www.43folders.com/2008/09/10/time-attention-creative-work">time and attention</a>, productivity, and making sure I could still do the things I enjoy, while spending as much time as possible with my family. </p>

<p>At that time I started to follow the blog <a href="http://blog.macademic.org/">Academic workflows on Mac</a>, I discovered the <a href="http://macpowerusers.com/">Mac power users</a>, <a href="brettterpstra.com">Brett Terpstra</a>, <a href="http://www.leancrew.com/all-this/">Dr. Drang</a>, and a whole lot of other extraordinary people, which in turn introduced me to a lot of neat things. For starters, things like <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown</a>, <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/project/nvalt/">nvAlt</a>, distraction free text editors, and many more cool stuff.  I must also admit that if it weren’t for my iOS device<sup id="fnref:foo2"><a href="#fn:foo2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup>, most of these things wouldn’t have happened. Simply, because lately I have very little time to sit in front of my desktop computer and go on about doing my thing of reading blogs, writing, etc.   It’s quite convenient to have this little–yet powerful–computer in your pocket and every time you can spare a couple of minutes, you just to take it out and start reading or typing (like I’m doing right now). It may seem strange to some, but I (think) I’m getting more things done now, than what I was a year or two ago. </p>

<p>Writing on my blog and following other blogs has been both a source of inspiration and motivation for me. To me, writing down my thoughts is an excellent exercise and helps me to stay focus. It allows me to clarify my train of thoughts, and most importantly it also allows me to step away from the more technical writing I usually (have to) do on scientific papers. </p>

<p>Many would argue that blogging takes a lot of your time. Some might even consider it  a waste of time.  I’m not going to go into much detail about this, however apparently many  people that think blogging is a waste of time seem to have enough time to write extremely long email replies<sup id="fnref:foo3"><a href="#fn:foo3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup>. That same message can serve as a basis for a post. As <a href="http://matt.might.net/articles/how-to-blog-as-an-academic/">Matt Might</a> says</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Before pressing send, ask yourself, should this answer be, “Reply,” “Reply to all,” or “Reply to public”?</p>

  <p>If you put effort into the reply, don’t waste it on a lucky few. Share it.</p>

  <p>– <strong>Matt Might</strong>, <a href="http://matt.might.net/articles/how-to-blog-as-an-academic/">6 Blog tips for busy academics</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>This has been a brief summary of my initiation in the blogosphere. I feel that blogging is much more than a hobby, it has become part of what I am, and that is why I care <em>so much</em> about it. </p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:foo">
      <p>At least that’s the idea. <a href="#fnref:foo" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:foo2">
      <p>An iPod touch 4th gen. <a href="#fnref:foo2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:foo3">
      <p>Or having spent the time elaborating an email signature that is generally longer than the email itself and seems more like a short autobiography.<a href="#fnref:foo3" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
